<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>First Baptist Church Muncie</title>
 <link href="http://london-news.demo/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://london-news.demo"/>
 <updated>2012-12-11T17:53:01-05:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Edward Hyde</name>
   <email>fake@mijingo.com</email>
 </author>

 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Giving God Credit</title>
 		<link href="/worship/Giving-God-Credit"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/Giving-God-Credit</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Psalm 29, David challenges us to give God credit in all things. But giving credit to God is more than lip service. It includes giving God what he is due. This plays out in the way in which we allocate our resources (our time, our money, our attention). And the promise of this psalm is that when we truly make God King (ascribe to Him all that is due Him), he blesses his people with peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Posture of Sacrifice</title>
 		<link href="/worship/Posture-of-Sacrifice"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/Posture-of-Sacrifice</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On this first Sunday of Epiphany, we consider the journey of the wise men. They travel a great distance and offer valuable gifts in order to worship Jesus. Their worship is a model of authentic worship. May we consider our own acts of worship as we engage the story together. Matthew 2:1-12&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Trusting God in the New Year</title>
 		<link href="/worship/Trusting-God-in-the-New-Year"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/Trusting-God-in-the-New-Year</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the final Sunday of 2012, we consider God&amp;rsquo;s calling in our life to live in various times. We will journey through the story of a small group at First Baptist Church Muncie. in 2012, God called this group to step out into something new and different. We will celebrate their courage and look forward to their new adventure in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Christmas Eve</title>
 		<link href="/worship/christmas-eve"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/christmas-eve</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The candlelight Christmas Eve service at First Baptist Church Muncie is a highlight of the Christmas season. Families gather to kick off Christmas celebrations in a beautifully decorated sanctuary. As we light Christmas eve candle, we remember the reason for our celebration. The story of Christmas is placed in the context of Christ&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice for us. There is no more appropriate way to begin Christmas than by receiving the most precious gift, His body broken for us and His blood shed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Mary's Song</title>
 		<link href="/worship/marys-song"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/marys-song</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we approach Christmas day, we are often overwhelmed with the stress of the holiday season. The hustle and bustle of buying gifts and preparing food often overshadow the true meaning of Christmas. On this third Sunday of Advent, we consider Mary&amp;rsquo;s response to God&amp;rsquo;s intervention in her life. It is a response of giving. May we be challenged through this story to submit our lives to God&amp;rsquo;s purposes. Luke 1:39-55&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Re-Focus</title>
 		<link href="/worship/re-focus"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/re-focus</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our lives are often overwhelmed by the anxiety of our current circumstances. In this Advent season, we are challenged to refocus on the greater realities. As Paul instructed the Philippians church, we must place our anxieties in God’s care. As we are able to do this, we will experience a piece that is beyond understanding. Philippians 4:4-7&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Joy</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Joy"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Joy</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year, our extended family is traveling to Indiana to spend time with us during the holidays. It is been 12 years since Christy&amp;rsquo;s sister has been to our home. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to avoid packing up and traveling south; but now we have to get the house ready for company. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal for you, but for my wife, everything has to be perfect. While I&amp;rsquo;m doing my best to dissuade her from major projects, she will do a bit of house-transformation before the company arrives. Last week, I found myself drawing out 3 foot letters for our mantle; Christy got the idea from Pinterest. She covered the wooden letters in gift wrap. I have to admit, they look pretty cool. The three letters spell out a common Christmas word; J-O-Y. We see this word plastered on billboards, coffee mugs and storefront displays throughout the season. But what does it mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems there is some confusion about the word &lt;em&gt;joy&lt;/em&gt;. Most equate it with happiness. But the word is much deeper. Happiness has to do with our circumstances. If your job is going well, relationships are strong, life is generally good, you might say that you are happy. But joy is has different roots; joy does not depend on our circumstances. The Scriptures instruct us to have &lt;em&gt;joy&lt;/em&gt;; they use the word &lt;em&gt;rejoice&lt;/em&gt;. In our text this week, Paul emphasizes this word. He says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Philippians 4:4 NIV) Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He doesn&amp;rsquo;t say it once; he says it twice. Imagine Paul dictating this letter. He tells his scribe, &amp;ldquo;rejoice in the Lord always&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;Let me make myself clear, I will say it again, rejoice!&amp;rdquo; Why does Paul say it twice? Why does he seem so emphatic? You see, to rejoice is independent of our circumstances. Paul is writing this letter from prison. He is awaiting a trial that may result in his death. It is in this context that he is able to instruct the church at Philippi. Their joy is to be rooted in God. As we study the context, we learn that the church in Philippi will experience intense persecution in the years to come. They will experience not-so-happy circumstances. Nevertheless, Paul encourages them to be joyful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul instructs the believers in Philippi to refocus their attention to God&amp;rsquo;s work in them. He challenges them to place their current anxieties at the feet of God; God will then exchange their worries for immeasurable peace. As we consider this text, we find this no easy task. Is it possible to trade our anxiety for God&amp;rsquo;s peace? As we gather this week, may God empower us to refocus in this way. May God give us the strength to rejoice, even when life is not happy. May we learn to live in Paul&amp;rsquo;s posture, depending on God in all things, and all circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Expectant</title>
 		<link href="/video/Expectant"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Expectant</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Paul&amp;rsquo;s letter to the Philippians allows us to peer into his heart. He is confident that God will complete the work He began in the Philippians church. He anticipates that this work one day come to an end as Jesus returns. His prayer for the Philippians is that they would also live in this anticipation of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return. As you and I explore this text, we are challenged to live in a posture of expectancy and urgency. God will one day return; this truth should drive us as we live out the gospel in our world. Philippians 1:3-11&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Focused on the End</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Focused-on-the-End"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Focused-on-the-End</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week, we talked about the need for urgency and anticipation in the Advent season. In particular, we discussed the need to look forward to Jesus&amp;rsquo;s second coming. We continue to consider this challenge in the coming weeks. For the next two weeks, we will be surveying Paul&amp;rsquo;s letter to the Philippians. As we examine the introduction, we see the anticipation of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return as a primary focus. On Sunday, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the way in which ancient letters were composed. There is a pattern or style of writing for these letters. As we examine the style, it gives us an understanding of Paul&amp;rsquo;s intentions. The section we will be studying is called a &amp;ldquo;Thanksgiving&amp;rdquo; element. In this part of the letter, the author offers a prayer for the recipient. As we read Paul&amp;rsquo;s prayer, we are able to peer into his heart; we are able to understand what he valued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have children, you pray for them. Sometimes you pray for academic achievement, healthy relationships and spiritual connection with God. You want the best for your kids; the way you pray for them indicates your priorities. In this section of Philippians, we are able to see Paul&amp;rsquo;s priorities for the church at Philippi. He prays for a unified body. If they are together in mind and spirit, it will mean spiritual health for them. Paul says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Philippians 1:10 NIV) so that you may be able to discern what is best and may be pure and blameless until the day of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see it in the text? Paul understands it necessary for the church to navigate waters of discord and strife. He knows that unity will produce holiness. It will not be easy; but their struggle will be only for a while. He says, &amp;ldquo;until the day of Christ.&amp;rdquo; In other words, when Jesus returns, all will be made right. The church will no longer need to strive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will look at other passages in the Pauline epistles regarding the day of Christ. We will see this day as central to the New Testament writers. And if it was foremost for them, it should be primary for us. As we continue through the season of Advent, may we learn to anticipate Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return. May we learn to balance the here and now with the promise of Christ&amp;rsquo;s return.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>His Return</title>
 		<link href="/video/his-return"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/his-return</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we approach the season of Advent, we are reminded that it is a season of urgency and expectancy. Jesus called his disciples to this posture of urgency and expectancy as he told them of his second coming. May we learn to live in the same posture as we look forward to Christ&amp;rsquo;s return.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Drunk</title>
 		<link href="/blog/drunk"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/drunk</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is hard to believe that December is almost here. We pulled our Christmas decorations out of the attic this weekend, turned on holiday music and transformed our interior and exterior decorations. We even indulged in a couple of holiday movies. It was a festive time for our family. We began our month-long celebration of Christmas. But Christmas is not yet here. It does not arrive until December 25. It may be more accurate to say that we began the &lt;em&gt;anticipation&lt;/em&gt; of Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Sunday, we celebrate the first Sunday of Advent. Advent is not Christmas. Advent is the season of anticipation prior to Christmas. We often lose sight of this as we have succumbed to cultural understandings of the holiday season. Yet, we should learn to live in Advent. This year, we will follow the lectionary passages during Advent. This year&amp;rsquo;s texts point to the second coming of Jesus. We will spend four Sundays considering the urgent and expectant posture of Scripture regarding Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While various interpretations have confused the matter, Scripture is clear that Jesus will return. This week, we will look at Jesus&amp;rsquo;s description of his return; next week, we will consider Paul&amp;rsquo;s writings to the Philippians about Christ&amp;rsquo;s return. How do we make sense of such a complex issue? When is it going to happen? How will it unfold? What clues do we have in Scripture about it? How are we to respond to Scripture&amp;rsquo;s teaching?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would take pages to unpack these questions. I will not attempt such a feat. Yet, I will point to Jesus&amp;rsquo;s advice to us; we are instructed toward a particular posture. Jesus warns,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 21:34 NIV)  Be careful, or your hearts will be weighed down with dissipation, drunkenness and the anxieties of life, and that day will close on you unexpectedly like a trap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Jesus saying? The word &lt;em&gt;dissipation&lt;/em&gt; describes a drunken headache, a hangover. Hangovers make it difficult to focus on work or chores. No doubt, the alcohol steals our attention. Jesus understands the impairment of worldly anxieties. He knows that we have the tendency to be tipsy on the cares of this world. They prevent our urgency, our anticipation of Jesus returning. When is the last time you thought about Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return? I have to admit that His coming does not often receive my focus. I seldom concentrate on Jesus&amp;rsquo;s promise to return. Yet, Scripture writers put intense emphasis on Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return. Jesus tells us to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 21:36 NIV)  Be always on the watch, and pray&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May we learn to share this anticipation. May we shake off the hangover of worldly anxieties. May we clearly look toward Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return with expectancy. I hope you will join as we worship in the season of Advent. I pray that our engagement of these texts will enlighten Jesus&amp;rsquo;s promise and our prayer,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Revelation 22:20 ESV) “Surely I am coming soon.” Amen. Come, Lord Jesus!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Orphans in China</title>
 		<link href="/video/orphans-in-china"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/orphans-in-china</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Katy Kessler, a student at Ball State, will be sharing about her experience this summer. She is an occupational therapy major who worked in an orphanage in China this summer. She will be sharing her story in worship.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Story of Jonah</title>
 		<link href="/video/dont-want-to-go"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/dont-want-to-go</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On November 18, we will worship in a combined worship service at 1045 a.m. The children will share a musical about the story of Jonah. We will also reflect the sermon on the call of God in our own lives. Jonah was more concerned about his own comfort, less concerned about following God’s mission in the world. We are challenged by his story to discard our own plans for God’s mission.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Reluctant</title>
 		<link href="/blog/reluctant"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/reluctant</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, the children will be presenting a musical on the story of Jonah. If you grew up in church, you know the story. A prophet is called by God to go to a savage city called Nineveh. He is hesitant &amp;hellip; no, he flat-out disobeys God. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t go to Nineveh; he takes off in the other direction. A storm batters his ship on his flight from God. In ancient times, tempests of this sort were understood as tantrums of the gods. Jonah&amp;rsquo;s shipmates cast lots to determine who has unsettled the gods. Jonah is identified as the culprit. To make a long story short, he is tossed into the sea, swallowed by a big fish, spit onto dry land. God comes to him a second time. This time he obeys. The story continues with Jonah unenthusiastically making the trek in the right direction. When he arrives in Nineveh, the people respond positively to his message. You might think he would be pleased. Rather, he is disappointed that God has offered salvation to the people of Nineveh. God uses a shade tree to communicate the value of all people to a disheartened Jonah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reflect on this story, we are reminded of our own tendency to walk away from God&amp;rsquo;s direction. God often calls us to unfavorable places. We resist by ignoring God or even going the other direction. I am not sure how God might be prompting you these days. Perhaps He is calling you to a new vocation or new city. Perhaps he is calling you to greater involvement in a particular ministry. While I cannot determine God&amp;rsquo;s voice in your life, I am certain that He calls us join Him in His mission. Joining God requires us to submit our way to His way. Jonah was not given a choice in the matter. In time, he was pressed to go God&amp;rsquo;s route. Perhaps our promptings will not include being swallowed by a fish. Maybe God will urge us in different ways. But God will not acquiesce to our resistance; he will not change His mind. He will not allow us to opt for plan B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May God give us the strength to heed his calling. May he grant us the joy of walking in His way. May we be unlike Jonah, ready to go with God wherever His mission takes us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>A Closing Scene</title>
 		<link href="/video/a-closing-scene"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/a-closing-scene</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the closing scenes of Genesis, we are reminded that God’s story is not over. As Jacob and Joseph pass from the scene, the promise of deliverance looms. As the curtain closes in Genesis, Joseph is embalmed and lies in an Egyptian coffin. Yet the story of God continues. As we gather, we are reminded of our connection with this story. We are reminded that God’s grace comes to fruition through the work of Jesus. As we connect and live in story of God, we are transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Permanent Grace</title>
 		<link href="/blog/permanent-grace"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/permanent-grace</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever received an undeserved gift? Was it difficult to accept? Did you envision someone showing up and taking it away? Perhaps it was hard to believe it could be yours? A few weeks ago, we took a group of teenagers to South Haven, Michigan for the weekend. We rented a couple of cabins attached to a bed and breakfast. Christy and I were able to spend time talking to one of the couples staying in the bed and breakfast. The man shared the story of winning a car. He entered a drawing; his name was announced on the radio. Friends called him to notify him of his fortune. He described peering at the prize in disbelief. Did this really happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not experienced this dynamic. But I could imagine a too-good-to-be-true feeling accompanying such a win. Maybe they will discover that it was a mistake; they will reclaim the prize and life will be as it should. We all have a tendency for skepticism when we get what we do not deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final chapter of Genesis, Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers experience this sort of cynicism. While they have experienced tremendous grace and provision, it is hard to believe that Joseph&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness is permanent. When Jacob dies, they expect justice to prevail. Joseph will finally get even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 50:15 NIV)  When Joseph’s brothers saw that their father was dead, they said, “What if Joseph holds a grudge against us and pays us back for all the wrongs we did to him?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They fear Joseph. Unwilling to speak to Joseph face to face, they send a message. Like a teenager breaking up with a boyfriend by sending a text message, they nervously ask Joseph for forgiveness. You might remember the earlier conversation between Joseph and his brothers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 45:5 NIV) And now, do not be distressed and do not be angry with yourselves for selling me here, because it was to save lives that God sent me ahead of you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph understands his destiny as ordained by God. He is not planning retribution. In fact, their message causes Joseph to weep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 50:17 NIV) When their message came to him, Joseph wept.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brother&amp;rsquo;s mistrust was painful. While he offered elaborate exoneration, his brothers doubted the permanence of his grace. They did not get it. They struggled to accept what they did not deserve. Joseph responds as he did earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 50:20 NIV) You intended to harm me, but God intended it for good to accomplish what is now being done, the saving of many lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us struggle to receive God&amp;rsquo;s grace. Even when we are able to accept what we do not deserve, we secretly wonder if our accounts will be audited. Will God decide to take a closer look and change His mind about us. We are like the brothers in this story. Yet, God&amp;rsquo;s grace is not temporary. The author of Hebrews reminds us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Hebrews 10: 23) Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God will not change his mind. Shifting circumstances will not alter His body broken for us nor his blood shed for us. May we learn, like Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers, to live in God&amp;rsquo;s permanent love for us. May we rest in the reality of his unchanging, undeserved, unconditional and absolute forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Destiny of Jacob's Sons</title>
 		<link href="/video/destiny-jacobs-sons"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/destiny-jacobs-sons</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Genesis 49, Jacob calls his sons to his deathbed for a blessing. He speaks powerful words that shape generations to come. His sons, forming the twelve tribes of Israel, will prepare the way for God to enter the world through Jesus. As the book of Genesis nears its end, we are reminded that the story continues as the people of God are now formed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Family Tree</title>
 		<link href="/blog/family-tree"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/family-tree</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I had an opportunity to connect with a bit of my family history. Dawson, Levi and I were traveling in the countryside of Georgia; we were on our way back from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freshairbarbecue.com/&quot; title=&quot;Home - Fresh Air Barbeque&quot;&gt;Fresh Air BBQ&lt;/a&gt; in Jackson. We passed my great-grandfather&amp;rsquo;s farm which sparked my interest in my lineage. We stopped by the land, walked around and even came across an old family cemetery. On that same visit to Georgia, my uncle gave me a copy of a written history of this land. It was fascinating to explore this story. While the story was filled with details, including specific dates, people and even copies of their wills, reading it raised my curiosity. I wondered how the various family lines developed. I wondered about the siblings. Where did they end up? Were there untold stories of love, war, romance, tragedy? How did their lives play out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we come to the final chapters of Genesis, we are given insight into the lineage of Jacob&amp;rsquo;s sons. On his deathbed, Jacob blesses his sons and prophesies about their descendants. We are reminded that Genesis is not an isolated story; it is the base for the remaining story of Scripture. It is the foundation for the people of God. The story does not end with the final verse of Genesis; it continues and includes many twists and turns. Eventually, the story includes Jesus&amp;rsquo;s arrival; His life, death and resurrection is the pinnacle of the story that begins in Genesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we gather at the Table to remember Jesus&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice for us this week, we are reminded that God was planning His work all the way back in Genesis. We are reminded that our lives are impacted by a larger story. We are included in this story as we live in God&amp;rsquo;s Kingdom. May we fall in love with God&amp;rsquo;s story. May we yearn to learn and live in His story. May we consider our role in His story and how our lives impact generations that follow us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Surprise Blessing</title>
 		<link href="/video/surprise-blessing"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/surprise-blessing</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we near the conclusion of the book of Genesis, Jacob is near death. Joseph and his sons pay a visit to his ailing father. Jacob’s actions of adopting and blessing his grandsons remind us that God often moves in surprising ways. As we learn to follow God, we discover that He often acts and moves in ways that we would not plan. Genesis 48&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Surprise</title>
 		<link href="/blog/surprise"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/surprise</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When is the last time you experienced a surprise? When did things turn out in a way different from what you expected? A few weeks ago, Dawson, Levi and I made a trip to Springfield, Illinois. Levi and Dawson wanted to attempt the Joe Rogers Chili Challenge (it was featured on Travel Channel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.travelchannel.com/tv-shows/man-v-food&quot; title=&quot;Man v. Food : TV Shows : Travel Channel&quot;&gt;Man vs. Food&lt;/a&gt;). You have to eat one bowl of Firebrand Chili and you get your name posted on the wall. It is no easy feat. To my surprise, both Dawson and Levi completed the challenge. Levi astonishingly was the youngest to ever complete the challenge. You can watch a video of Dawson &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T1ETfUFNvC8&amp;amp;amp;feature=plcp&quot; title=&quot;Dawson eating Joe Rogers - YouTube&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and Levi &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Io1h9aT6iGo&amp;amp;amp;feature=plcp&quot; title=&quot;Levi at Joe Rogers chili - YouTube&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I was surprised at how it all turned out. I thought I would be encouraging the boy&amp;rsquo;s effort as we walked out; yet we left celebrating their victory over the Firebrand Chili.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s text leaves us surprised. Jacob is near death and ready to bless his sons. As you may know, it was common practice to bless the oldest son, passing on the family name, land and leadership. Yet Jacob has an alternative plan. As we have seen before, God likes to mix it up; His ways are unpredictable. Join us on Sunday as we walk though Genesis 48 together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reflect on this story, we are reminded that God&amp;rsquo;s calling cannot be mapped out. We are challenged with a willingness for flexibility. We are often adverse to change, unwilling to carry out ministry in a different way. Maybe God would surprise our methods with new callings. May we consistently be open to God&amp;rsquo;s surprises. May we be willing to follow him into the unknown, the difficult, the new.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Cultural Changes</title>
 		<link href="/blog/cultural-changes"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/cultural-changes</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are living in a transitional period of time in the life of First Baptist Church Muncie. In many ways, we find ourselves in a drastically different world. Muncie is not the same city that it was 50 years ago; the world is not the same world. We have moved from being in the center of the community to being on the fringes. I am not talking about geographically, but culturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who&amp;rsquo;ve been around a while, you may notice more empty pews these days. This is not a characteristic unique to First Baptist Church Muncie. It&amp;rsquo;s happening all over the country. Thom Rainer tells us that &lt;strong&gt;65%&lt;/strong&gt; of the Builder generation (born before 1946) attends church on a weekly basis.  The next generation (Boomers, born between the years 1946 and 1964) is about&lt;strong&gt; 35%&lt;/strong&gt;. Their kids (Generation X, born generally from the early 60s to the early 80s) attend church at rates around &lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;. The youngest generation (termed Generation Y, born from the mid 80s on) attends church at about &lt;strong&gt;4%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is mind boggling to see such a drop in church attendance. No doubt, our world is changing. It is clear that we cannot continue to pretend that we exist in 1950. We are called, as a congregation, to navigate these cultural changes as we follow the Spirit of God. In many ways, we are returning to the world much like the early church. We, as the church, are no longer in the center of society. We no longer have the prestige, the power, the privilege of building a big building and watching droves of people flock through our doors. Our posture will need to change; we will have to focus outwardly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of young adults has been discussing the cultural shifts and considering ways to navigate the changes in our world. At the beginning of 2013, a small group will be experimenting with new models of ministry, in order to reach our community with the message of Christ. I hope that each of you will pray that God will direct First Baptist Church Muncie as we respond to God&amp;rsquo;s leading. I am sure that God will resource this congregation to fulfill His calling. You will hear more of these experimental ministries in the coming months. I mentioned them now so that you will join me in praying for God&amp;rsquo;s leading as we plan.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Jealousy</title>
 		<link href="/blog/jealousy"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/jealousy</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to be jealous? Sometimes you read of a jealous boyfriend or girlfriend. They are careful about their significant other; they don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone else to share in their relationship. Other times you hear of jealous siblings. They find joy in the failures of their brothers and sisters. Somehow, they feel as though they are lifted up when others fall. Surely, jealousy is a sin. We are reminded in Scripture to exhibit an attitude of gratefulness in contrast to jealousy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core of jealousy is a forgetfulness of what we have been given. We focus on what others have received, neglecting our own gifts. We also use the word envy to describe such behavior. We speak of someone as “green with envy” when they are upset by the fortune of another. We have all felt this way at one time or another. Maybe it was a job promotion for a coworker or a successful test score for a sibling. We are unable to celebrate the good in their life because we are upset that we did not receive. When we harbor such feelings, we fail to be grateful for the gifts that God has given us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s story, Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers relocate to Egypt in order to survive the famine. Significant grace is extended and spite of their previous failures. They had sold their brother into slavery; they did not deserve to be rescued. But in this story, they are given another chance to respond. Joseph blesses his brothers with new clothes. Again, they receive what they do not deserve. But they will be tested. Benjamin receives five new garments. As before, favoritism is given to one brother. How will be other brothers respond? Twenty years earlier, they responded with jealousy and sold the privileged brother into slavery. Joseph knows their tendency. He warns them,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 45:24 NIV) &amp;hellip; Don’t quarrel on the way!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems kind of crazy that this would be a possibility. They had been given far more than they deserved. Grace has been extended to them. Why would they quarrel? They should be celebrating. But when we stop and think about it, we have all reacted in this way at one time or another. Our tendency is to focus on what we do not have rather than what we have been given. Our tendency is to be jealous of our siblings, our coworkers, our neighbors. This story is a reminder to choose gratefulness over jealousy. It is a reminder that we have been given what we do not deserve. We have no reason to be jealous, to be envious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we delve into this week&amp;rsquo;s story, may we be reminded of our own propensity to focus on what others have received. May we be reminded of the tremendous grace that God has given each of us through Jesus Christ. And may this grace overpower our temptation to focus on what others have received.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Office Hours</title>
 		<link href="/blog/office-hours"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/office-hours</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, my son&amp;rsquo;s friend (a middle schooler) asked me a question. Knowing that I am a pastor, he wondered about my work week. &amp;ldquo;What do you do all week?,&amp;rdquo; he asked, &amp;ldquo;Do you clean the church or something?&amp;rdquo; He pictured me sitting in my office during the week with little to do. Maybe vacuuming the sanctuary or cleaning windows would keep me from getting too bored. While we may laugh at this kid&amp;rsquo;s honesty, perhaps some of you wonder how I spend my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is honest to say that I never run out of work. Many high-profile pastors have struggled with issues of life and time management. Some have neglected their families in light of a &amp;ldquo;higher&amp;rdquo; calling. Others have neglected their bodies, failing to exercise and eat right due to hurried schedules. A few weeks ago, Matt and I spent an entire day outlining our job/ministry descriptions. It became clear that we rarely work a 40 hour week; most of our weeks are 55-60 hours. So what takes up all this time? Why are pastors so busy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Matt and I serve different roles in this congregation, our work patterns are similar. We spend time preparing sermons or planning worship, leading teams of volunteers in ministry, reading current literature on theology and church life, caring for those who are sick or bereaved, communicating (through church publications or blogs), connecting with the larger Muncie community and spending time in relationship with people. Our work day is not 9-to-5, it is unpredictable and we don&amp;rsquo;t always have a weekly pattern. Evening meetings and late night emergency calls sometimes interrupt family time and sleep. Indeed, we have to work hard to keep balance in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it may be difficult to define the work of a pastor, the primary purpose of our role is to lead this congregation in following the calling of God in our lives. This may involve conversation in a coffee shop, lunch with someone who is struggling, a visit with a hospital patient, connecting with other church leaders in the community or sequestering for prayer and study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our work often needs to take place outside of the church office. Because of the fluctuating nature of our work, it is difficult to predict where we may be at any given time on any given day. If you drive to the church office, you may or may not find us there. Nevertheless, I want you to know that your pastoral staff is accessible. Our cell phone numbers are published in the church bulletin; please feel free to call or text us. We will gladly speak with you on the phone or schedule an appointment. Some may feel hesitant about calling; it may seem that your concern or question is insignificant. Therefore, we are providing a staff contact request form in the church office. Please fill free to fill this out to request a contact with Will, Robert, Matt or myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a 9-to-5 job seems appealing; predictability in schedule offers benefits. However, I love the work that God has called me to. And while I am rarely needed to vacuum or clean windows in the church, I do receive such assignments at home.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Extreme Grace</title>
 		<link href="/blog/extreme-grace"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/extreme-grace</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we lived in Springfield, Illinois, a friend (and member of our church) worked on the Governor&amp;rsquo;s staff. I was pleasantly surprised when he offered me and Christy tickets to the Inaugural Ball. It was pretty cool to be involved in a VIP event of this sort. Our coats were taken at the door; we were invited to enjoy an unbelievable display of prime rib, seafood and all kinds of hors d'oeuvres. We were able to dance, feast and rub shoulders with celebrities. We clearly did not belong at the event. I was a youth pastor, not a political supporter. Yet, we enjoyed the elevated treatment for one evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s story, Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers make the trek to Egypt in search of food. When they arrive, Joseph recognizes them, but they don&amp;rsquo;t know Joseph. Joseph has a plan. He accuses the brothers of espionage. Terrified, they return home only to find the silver (the money used to buy the grain) in their bags. Now they will be accused of robbery. It seems that everything is going wrong. They interpret their misfortune as God&amp;rsquo;s punishment for selling Joseph into slavery. They are instructed to return with their younger brother, Benjamin. In time, they return because of the severity of the famine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they arrive in Egypt (for the second time), they are frightened, uncertain; they fear they will be enslaved or killed. But their treatment is not what they expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 43:33 NIV) The men had been seated before him in the order of their ages, from the firstborn to the youngest; and they looked at each other in astonishment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They could not believe what was happening. In their minds, they deserved death. They sold Joseph into slavery and God was enacting revenge. You could also make the case that Joseph should have taken his chance for retaliation. However, they are invited to feast, to enjoy the plenty in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 43:34 NIV) When portions were served to them from Joseph’s table, Benjamin’s portion was five times as much as anyone else’s. So they feasted and drank freely with him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benjamin gets more food, but all the brothers are feasting and drinking freely. This is a beautiful story of grace. The brothers are astonished by such generosity. Their treatment defies fairness. Yet, they receive and are blessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we think about this story, we will come to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Table together on Sunday. We are welcomed to a table that we don&amp;rsquo;t deserve. We have experienced an abundant grace that covers our sins. It is crucial that we live in this grace each day. I hope that you can join us on Sunday as we explore this story and remember together the blood shed for us, the body broken for us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Reliance</title>
 		<link href="/blog/reliance"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/reliance</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In our culture, we are often told that we can accomplish whatever we want. We simply need to give it enough energy, focus; if we simply work hard enough, it will be ours. While there is merit in such advice, we may want to rethink how we guide our children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s story, Joseph is finally released from prison. His long awaited emancipation comes as a result of dream interpretation skills. His freedom did not come as soon as Joseph may have hoped, but it comes nonetheless. The cupbearer forgot to bring up Joseph&amp;rsquo;s name on his initial release (Gen. 40:23). Yet when Pharaoh experienced dream problems some two years later, he recalls the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 41:12 NIV) Now a young Hebrew was there with us, a servant of the captain of the guard. We told him our dreams, and he interpreted them for us, giving each man the interpretation of his dream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did Joseph interpret the dreams, but he nailed it. Maybe he would be able to help Pharaoh. So Joseph is cleaned up and brought before the King. Pharaoh tells Joseph his dream and asked him if he would be able to interpret it. I love Joseph&amp;rsquo;s response. It may be a clue as to why God would have chosen Joseph. Look at how Joseph responds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 41:16 NIV) “I cannot do it,” Joseph replied to Pharaoh, “but God will give Pharaoh the answer he desires.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This verse is key. Joseph does not strut in, celebrating his ability to interpret dreams. He humbly confesses that he is incapable without God&amp;rsquo;s assistance. Joseph is reliant on God&amp;rsquo;s power. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s dependence on God models the proper posture for you and me. God does incredible things through Joseph. In fact, in one day he goes from a prisoner to second in command in Egypt. One might chalk up the success to Joseph&amp;rsquo;s ability. Yet the author of Genesis credits his humility and willingness to be used by God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pharaoh notices that Joseph has an intense connection with God. He wants someone like this in charge during the prophesied famine. Pharaoh says to Joseph,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 41:39 NIV) Since God has made all this known to you, there is no one so discerning and wise as you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt that Pharaoh understood Joseph&amp;rsquo;s connection with God. Yet he understands that Joseph operates out of a power not his own. He senses Joseph&amp;rsquo;s ability to remain dependent on God. In a world where self-esteem and self-promotion are valued, may we learn to rely on God. May we learn to exhibit the posture of Joseph. May we confess our inability as we seek God&amp;rsquo;s ability to do the impossible through us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Disappointed</title>
 		<link href="/blog/disappointed"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/disappointed</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I hate going to the grocery store on my way home from work. Long lines are common at this time of the day. I guess everyone waits until they are heading home from work to stop by the store. You have to stand there and wait! The magazines at the checkout counter may entertain for short time; but after a bit, I find myself impatient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is waiting so hard? It seems partly because we live in a world of instant gratification. We can grab dinner without ever having to emerge from our vehicle. If our order is incorrect and we have to walk into the restaurant, we are irate. In a busy and hurried world, waiting is not easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our story this week, we find Joseph in prison. You may remember that he is incarcerated for allegedly raping Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife. Unjustly accused, his time in prison must have tested his patience. In time, Joseph encounters two men disturbed by dreams. The cupbearer and the baker are two of Pharaoh&amp;rsquo;s trusted servants. We are not sure how they ended up in prison, but they must have offended Pharaoh in some way. Joseph, in charge of all the prisoners, has an opportunity to get to know these men. God gives him the ability to interpret their troublesome dreams. For one, the dream meant freedom; for the other, it meant death. As the cupbearer finds freedom, it seems Joseph&amp;rsquo;s will get his ticket out of prison. Yet we read,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 40:23 NIV) The chief cupbearer, however, did not remember Joseph; he forgot him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must have been a stunning disappointment for Joseph. It seemed that God had given him the ability to interpret the cupbearer&amp;rsquo;s dream so that he would be granted freedom. It appeared that God was moving Joseph toward freedom. Yet Joseph finds himself let down and questioning God&amp;rsquo;s intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us who know the end of the story, we are okay with Joseph being in prison a bit longer. But for Joseph, dismay and doubt must have ruled his thoughts. You see, he did not know the story&amp;rsquo;s ending. He had no idea what God was going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You and I often find ourselves in this place. Perhaps we&amp;rsquo;re disappointed because God isn&amp;rsquo;t providing in the way we imagined. Maybe a job application was refused, a scholarship was denied or medical report returned ominous results. We are left questioning, doubting or disappointed. In times like these, we must learn to trust the One who sees the future, the One who determines all things. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s story reminds us that God&amp;rsquo;s timing is perfect. May we learn to trust as we wait on God. May we learn that He has our best interests in mind. He is faithful, no matter our circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 

</feed>