<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>First Baptist Church Muncie</title>
 <link href="http://fbcmuncie.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://fbcmuncie.org"/>
 <updated>2013-02-18T15:45:04-05:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Wade Allen</name>
   <email>wade@fbcmuncie.org</email>
 </author>

 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Broken and Poured Out</title>
 		<link href="/worship/Broken-and-Poured-Out"/>
 		<updated>2013-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/Broken-and-Poured-Out</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The story of Mary pouring perfume on Jesus his feet during an evening banquet is a model for us. Out of all the people in the room that evening, Mary was most insane with what God was doing in the world. While her action draws criticism, her extravagant gift honors Jesus. Jesus commends her for her sacrifice. As we study this passage together, we will reflect on our own willingness to serve in this posture. John 12:1-8&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Day God Ran</title>
 		<link href="/worship/The-Day-God-Ran"/>
 		<updated>2013-03-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/The-Day-God-Ran</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We often envision God as stern and demanding. Yet a series of parables in Luke 15 gives us a different picture of God. God is undignified in His search for what is lost. He goes to extreme measures to reclaim His treasured possesions. As we delve into the infamous parable of the prodigal son, we see God&amp;rsquo;s lavish love for us. Luke 15&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Repentance and Restoration</title>
 		<link href="/worship/Repentance-and-Restoration"/>
 		<updated>2013-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/Repentance-and-Restoration</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As Jesus encounters tragedy, he corrects the common understandings of his day. While the religious pious point fingers at the sins of others, Jesus directs them toward examining their own hearts. He warns them of coming destruction if they fail to repent. As we engage this text, we are challenged to abandon fruitless religion for intimate relationship with God. Luke 13:1-9&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Transformed</title>
 		<link href="/worship/Transformed"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/worship/Transformed</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the disciples look back on their experience with Jesus, they remember one particular event. At the time, they did not talk about it. But looking back, they understand the significance of a mountaintop journey with Jesus. As we consider Luke 9:28–36, we are challenged in our own tendencies to stay on the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Stepping Out</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Stepping-Out"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Stepping-Out</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Sunday, we will be exploring one of the strangest stories in the Gospels. Jesus' ministry is coming to a close. He is talking more and more about leaving, about dying. I am not sure that the disciples fully understood his predictions. Midway through Luke 9, we are able to peer into a private conversation between Jesus and his disciples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 9:18-20 NIV) Once when Jesus was praying in private and his disciples were with him, he asked them, “Who do the crowds say I am?” &amp;hellip; “But what about you?” he asked. “Who do you say I am?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter is the first to speak up. He confirms that Jesus is the Christ. Yet Peter does not seem to comprehend the full ramifications of this claim. Jesus explains,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 9:22 NIV) The Son of Man must suffer many things and be rejected by the elders, chief priests and teachers of the law, and he must be killed and on the third day be raised to life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus clarifies his mission and the requirements of his followers in fulfilling the work of his Kingdom. I imagine a lot of head scratching in the group that day. You would think they might begin to grasp his words. But the next story reveals their lack of understanding. We read,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 9:28 NIV) About eight days after Jesus said this, he took Peter, John and James with him and went up onto a mountain to pray.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we will explore this encounter on the mountain. It looks more like a sci-fi movie than a story from first century Palestine. Jesus lights up in an unexplainable white glow. Visitors, who have been dead for hundreds of years (Moses and Elijah), show up. They are in conversation with Jesus. In the end, the disciples are left speechless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key point in this story is Peter&amp;rsquo;s failed attempt to set up shop on the mountain. Peter sees the spectacular happenings and longs to stay. He suggests setting up tents and worshiping on the mountain. It is almost as if he completely forgot Jesus' words from eight days ago. Perhaps he remembers them but desperately wants to avoid them. Either way, he completely misses what God is doing. God is confirming Jesus' identity and planning the redemption of the world. Peter wants to hide out on the mountain in selfish comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we are quick to mock Peter&amp;rsquo;s actions, we struggle with the same desire. We are sometimes eager to set up cozy environments. We enjoy the serenity of living apart from the world. Yet, God calls us to join Him on His mission. He refuses to condone our self-centered ministries. We must get into the world if we truly desire to follow Jesus. May we be attentive to the work of His Kingdom. May we eagerly join Him as he transforms our world through you and me.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Temptations</title>
 		<link href="/video/The-Temptations"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/The-Temptations</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shortly after Jesus&amp;rsquo;s baptism, he travels into the wilderness to be tempted by the devil. For 40 days, he eats nothing and battles temptation. As we explore Luke&amp;rsquo;s account of these temptations, we are challenged in our own temptations. Jesus models for us successful resistance to the evil one. Luke 4:1-13&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Dealing with Temptation</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Dealing-with-Temptation"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Dealing-with-Temptation</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We rarely order dessert when we go out to eat. Large serving sizes leave us incapable of digesting more food. However, there is usually a small display with full color pictures showcasing the kitchen&amp;rsquo;s confections. Many have given names to the after-dinner delights. When chocolate is the main ingredient, you will sometimes see the word &lt;em&gt;temptation&lt;/em&gt; in the description. We understand the ramifications of indulging in a calorie packed, sugary cake or ice cream. Our waistline will suffer as a result. Yet, it is hard to resist the savory treat. While we have lightened the word, relegating it to eating a piece of cake, true temptation is powerful and dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s text, Jesus is led by the Spirit into the wilderness to be tempted by Satan. Luke records the culmination of a forty-day fast in which Satan tempts Jesus in three ways. On Sunday, we will discuss the intricacy of each temptation. Yet, all three temptations have a common theme. Satan is attempting to separate Jesus from the Father and Spirit. He questions Jesus' role as the Son of God by steering him away from His calling. In each instance, Satan offers Jesus an alternative route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus' willingness to experience temptation verifies his desire to identify with you and me. The author of Hebrews describes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Hebrews 4:15 NIV) For we do not have a high priest who is unable to sympathize with our weaknesses, but we have one who has been tempted in every way, just as we are &amp;mdash; yet was without sin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But more than that, Jesus models for us how to handle temptation. Each of our temptations will be different. Satan knows our weaknesses and capitalizes on our inclinations to stray from God&amp;rsquo;s design. But we can draw from Jesus' experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, Jesus is Spirit-led and Spirit-empowered as he encounters temptation. Luke begins this story by telling us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 4:1 NIV) Jesus, full of the Holy Spirit, returned from the Jordan and was led by the Spirit in the desert&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that Jesus is filled with the Spirit of God. He is the Son of God. How could He not be filled with the Spirit? Yet, this is key to Luke&amp;rsquo;s description of Jesus' temptations. Jesus is not operating in his own strength. Think about it, He has not had food for forty days. He must have been famished, mentally and physically drained. But Jesus does not find strength in the physical. He draws on the power of the Spirit as he battles the Evil One. It is easy to dismiss a Spirit-filled life as reserved for Jesus. Yet, you and I are promised strength that only comes through the power of the Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, Jesus responds to each temptation with Scripture. He retaliates with God&amp;rsquo;s Word in each case. Jesus' knowledge and dependence on Scripture is primary. If Jesus, the Son of God, uses Scripture to battle temptation, so should we. If we are biblically illiterate, we are walking on thin ice in regards to temptation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us on Sunday as we delve into this text. May we learn to appropriately respond to the temptations in our lives. May we look to Jesus as our model and guide.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Hearts Follow Treasure</title>
 		<link href="/video/Hearts-Follow-Treasure"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Hearts-Follow-Treasure</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jesus instructs us to be careful where we place our stockpiles, our treasures. He instructs us to build them in eternal places. As we do so, our hearts will gravitate toward those places. Matthew 6:19-21&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Hearts in the Right Place</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Hearts-in-the-Right-Place"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Hearts-in-the-Right-Place</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have to be honest; this week&amp;rsquo;s sermon will not be preached for the first time on Sunday. I shared this message at Taylor University in January. When I was asked to speak at Taylor&amp;rsquo;s chapel, I felt that this text would be especially applicable to college students. The stage of life, often called late adolescence, is a season of learning and discovery. In this stage, we are often building patterns that will continue for the rest of our life. I wanted to challenge these college students with the idea of stewardship, of taking what we have been given and using it for the Kingdom of God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we have mentioned already, stewardship is more than money. Sure, it involves money, but it also involves our time and energy. In this week&amp;rsquo;s text, Jesus offers incredible insight into how our investments affect our hearts. The teaching is succinct,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Matthew 6:19–21 NIV) “Do not store up for yourselves treasures on earth, where moth and rust destroy, and where thieves break in and steal. But store up for yourselves treasures in heaven, where moth and rust do not destroy, and where thieves do not break in and steal. For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we will explore this teaching in detail. We will consider what it means to &lt;em&gt;store up treasures&lt;/em&gt;. We will reflect on the eternal ramifications of earthly investments compared to heavenly investments. But for the purpose of this blog entry, I want to focus on this last sentence. Jesus said,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Matthew 6:21 NIV) For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus understands our inner being. He formed us, created us and designed us. He knows how we work. Jesus recognizes that our hearts will naturally gravitate to the places where we put our time, attention and money (our treasure). It is just how it works. This is an important truth as we talk about stewardship. We often picture God in need of our resources. We reason, &amp;ldquo;We should give back to God so that the church can function, the poor can have their needs met and missionaries can travel abroad.&amp;rdquo; But the reality is that God already has all the resources He needs. God does not need us to give. We read in Psalm 50,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Psalms 50:9–10 NIV) I have no need of a bull from your stall or of goats from your pens, for every animal of the forest is mine, and the cattle on a thousand hills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God wants us to faithfully steward our resources because he wants our hearts. God deeply desires that our hearts be integrated into the Kingdom of God. And He knows that our hearts will follow our treasure. Do you have trouble thinking about the things of God? Do you long to be more connected to your heavenly Father? Do you want your heart to be in sync with God&amp;rsquo;s heart? The solution is simple. Begin to place your treasure in the things of God; your heart will naturally follow. May our hearts gravitate toward God&amp;rsquo;s heart. May we learn to &lt;em&gt;store up&lt;/em&gt; in the right places so that our most valuable treasure, our heart, will be in the right place.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Two Masters</title>
 		<link href="/video/Two-Masters"/>
 		<updated>2013-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Two-Masters</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Soozi Whitten Ford teaches from Luke 16:13-15. Soozi is the Executive Minister for American Baptist Churches in Indiana and Kentucky. She has recently moved to Indiana in 2012. She has served the American Baptist Churches USA nationally in the area of stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Body of Christ</title>
 		<link href="/video/Body-of-Christ"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Body-of-Christ</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Paul uses the illustration of anatomy to describe the way we function as a church. A physical body has many parts, but it is one unit. Each part has a vital role in is health. As we study 1 Corinthians 12:12-31a, we are each challenged to steward our time and energy in ways that strengthen the body of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Risk</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Risk"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Risk</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was engaged in my doctoral work at Northern Seminary, I read extensively about the ways in which culture and the church are shifting. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a seminary student to see that both society and the church are changing. Sociologists will tell you that younger generations are less active in the life of the church. The numbers vary, yet the decline is anything but minimal. Some reports indicate that church attendance has moved from 65% in the Builder generation to only 4% in the current generation of twenty-somethings. How is the church going to respond?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the books in my studies was written by Eddie Gibbs,; it is entitled &lt;em&gt;ChurchNext: Quantum Changes in How We Do Ministry&lt;/em&gt;. The book was written in 2000 (it is almost 13 years old); yet his predictions have proved to be accurate. Gibbs describes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the following chapters is to attempt to identify some of the major storm centers through which churches have to navigate. (Gibbs, 11)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it would be impossible to detail the entire book in this article, Gibbs describes the need to experiment with different models of ministry. He explains essential skill-sets for pastors that include deciphering the complex changes in our world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pastors must be equally skilled in exegeting both Scripture and culture, bringing the understanding derived from this interplay to the task of applying biblically grounded insights to the issues of postmodernity.  They are challenged not just to be able to think clearly but to have the nerve and faith to act decisively in navigating through stormy and uncharted waters. (Gibbs, 32)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the waters of our world are stormy. We will not be able to continue business as usual. We will need to discern God&amp;rsquo;s Spirit as we respond to our changing culture. Gibbs describes the posture of the congregation as willing to take risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a culture of chaos, experimentation and risk taking are the order of the day. (Gibbs, 34)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could Gibbs be right? Could it be that we will need to take more risks than our fathers and grandfathers? Could it be that we need to discard the old adage, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;ve always done it that way before,&amp;rdquo; if we want to survive? This year, we may be faced with difficult decisions as a congregation. Budgetary constraints may force us to reconsider how we utilize our resources. We may need to discontinue or reform ministries that have existed for years. I ask each attendee and member to prayerfully consider a new posture of flexibility and risk. It may be the only way to chart the treacherous waters of today&amp;rsquo;s world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>A Hurt Toe</title>
 		<link href="/blog/A-Hurt-Toe"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/A-Hurt-Toe</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several months ago, I showed up on Sunday morning wearing one of Dawson&amp;rsquo;s sandals. It looked kind of funny wearing a dress shoe on one foot and a Jordan sandal on the other. But I was not trying to make a fashion statement; my attire was a matter of necessity. A few nights before, I was washing dishes. A drinking glass slipped out of my hand and crashed onto the counter; a shard of glass pierced my big toe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am no stranger to foot injuries. Several years ago, my toenail popped off as I ascended from a subway station in Atlanta. I caught it on the cement stairs while wearing flip-flops. Before that, I twisted my ankle while jogging, fracturing a bone in my foot. Adam Fink commented, &amp;ldquo;You tend to hurt your foot a lot.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is amazing how dysfunction in your smallest body part can throw a wrench in your day to day activities. A simple walk upstairs can turn into a multi-faceted ordeal. In this week&amp;rsquo;s text, Paul uses the analogy of the body and its parts as he teaches the church about spiritual gifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(1 Corinthians 12:12 NIV) The body is a unit, though it is made up of many parts; and though all its parts are many, they form one body.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul describes the tension between a unified body and the variety of its parts. We are one, yet we function in an assortment of areas. We must keep this tension in mind as we think about spiritual gifts. We function in various ways; yet each part is necessary and contributes to the whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my disabled toe was healing, I was unable to carry out my daily workout; I was impaired. The injured body part affected the whole body. As we gather on Sunday, we will consider Paul&amp;rsquo;s description of the body and its parts. May we get a clear picture of a healty body, living into its full potential as the church of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Stewardship</title>
 		<link href="/video/Body-of-Christ-One"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Body-of-Christ-One</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Doug Gregg preaches a sermon on stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Giving God Credit</title>
 		<link href="/video/Giving-God-Credit"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Giving-God-Credit</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Psalm 29, David challenges us to give God credit in all things. But giving credit to God is more than lip service. It includes giving God what he is due. This plays out in the way in which we allocate our resources (our time, our money, our attention). And the promise of this psalm is that when we truly make God King (ascribe to Him all that is due Him), he blesses his people with peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Ascribe</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Ascribe"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Ascribe</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, we turn to a Psalm in our stewardship series. A while back, we did a series on the Psalms; we discovered the rich treasury of poetry and reflection in this ancient collection. Psalm 29, this week&amp;rsquo;s text, was written by David.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David is one interesting character to say the least. His story includes all the components of a good movie. From humble beginnings to an ascension to power, David&amp;rsquo;s story includes tension, drama, attempted murder, friendship and betrayal. As King, his story gets more interesting. The plot involves adultery, murder, father and son rivalries, forgiveness and restoration. By the time it is all over, David&amp;rsquo;s kingdom is perhaps the greatest in Israel&amp;rsquo;s history. From worldly standards, he was tremendously successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With success comes the potential for arrogance. It is easy to believe that we are somehow responsible for our good fortune. But David is careful to give God credit. He writes in Psalm 29,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Psalms 29:1–2 NIV) Ascribe to the LORD, O mighty ones, ascribe to the LORD glory and strength. Ascribe to the LORD the glory due his name; worship the LORD in the splendor of his holiness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three times, David uses the word &lt;em&gt;ascribe&lt;/em&gt;. This seems to be a key word in this psalm. The word is translated different ways in the Old Testament (come, choose, bring), but the most common translation is &lt;em&gt;give&lt;/em&gt;. It has to do with giving someone what they are due. David is reminding us that God is due the glory. In other words, we are to credit God for all He has done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It may have been easy for David to take credit for his success. No doubt, he was a powerful and effective leader. Yet he understands his success as coming from God. As we consider our lives, we must be careful to &lt;em&gt;ascribe the glory&lt;/em&gt; to God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us on Sunday as we explore how this plays out in our lives. David&amp;rsquo;s admonition is more than lip service. To adequately credit God involves action. The foundational notion of crediting God challenges us to consider our calendar, our financial resources, our talents and our energy. Are we giving God credit in the way we use the gifts He has given us?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Posture of Sacrifice</title>
 		<link href="/video/Posture-of-Sacrifice"/>
 		<updated>2013-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Posture-of-Sacrifice</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On this first Sunday of Epiphany, we consider the journey of the wise men. They travel a great distance and offer valuable gifts in order to worship Jesus. Their worship is a model of authentic worship. May we consider our own acts of worship as we engage the story together. Matthew 2:1-12&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Treasure</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Treasure"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Treasure</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do you ever pay attention to Nativity scenes? Sometimes they seem far too clean. Mary and Joseph look more like royalty than ordinary teenagers from Nazareth. The shepherds seldom appear as rag-tag as first century sheep herders would have been. Many Nativity scenes include Magi; wise men from the East come to worship the baby Jesus. While it is unlikely that they stood around with the shepherds (they arrive at a house in Matthew 2:11), the Magi play an important role in the birth narrative of Jesus. Their worship serves as a model for authentic worship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Sunday, the church around the world celebrates Epiphany. The story of the wise men reminds us that Jesus came for the entire world. We find pagans bowing down and presenting gifts to Jesus. As I prepared for this week&amp;rsquo;s sermon, one word in Matthew&amp;rsquo;s gospel rang out. I had not noticed it before. Matthew tells us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Matthew 2:11 NIV) Then they opened their treasures and presented him with gifts of gold and of incense and of myrrh.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had always pictured modern Christmas presents with bows and shiny paper. But the word used in the text describes more than trinkets. The word that is translated &lt;em&gt;treasures&lt;/em&gt; is only used 16 times in the entire New Testament. The word is sometimes translated as &lt;em&gt;storehouse&lt;/em&gt;. It is more than a gift box; it describes a treasure chest of great value. Jesus spoke of treasure,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Matthew 6:19-21 NIV) &amp;ldquo;Do not store up for yourselves &lt;strong&gt;treasures&lt;/strong&gt; on earth, where moth and rust destroy, and where thieves break in and steal. But store up for yourselves &lt;strong&gt;treasures&lt;/strong&gt; in heaven, where moth and rust do not destroy, and where thieves do not break in and steal. For where your &lt;strong&gt;treasure&lt;/strong&gt; is, there your heart will be also.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jesus uses the word three times in this teaching. This is the same Greek word that Matthew uses to describe the gifts of the Magi. This connection is significant. The Magi bring valuable, sacrificial offerings to the baby Jesus. We are instructed by the adult Jesus to store our treasure in eternal, Kingdom places. In other words, where we place our treasure is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pagan Magi model worship for us. They lay their treasure at the feet of Jesus. Most Nativity scenes depict the Magi in a posture of bowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Matthew 2:11 NIV) they bowed down and worshiped him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But their bowing extends beyond their posture. It includes their giving treasure, they place their valuables at the feet of the eternal King. May our worship be more than lip service. May our worship be more than enduring a few songs and sermon each week. May it include placing our treasure, our sacrificial offerings into the work of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Trusting God in the New Year</title>
 		<link href="/video/Trusting-God-in-the-New-Year"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Trusting-God-in-the-New-Year</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the final Sunday of 2012, we consider God&amp;rsquo;s calling in our life to live in various times. We will journey through the story of a small group at First Baptist Church Muncie. in 2012, God called this group to step out into something new and different. We will celebrate their courage and look forward to their new adventure in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Christmas Eve</title>
 		<link href="/video/christmas-eve"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/christmas-eve</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The candlelight Christmas Eve service at First Baptist Church Muncie is a highlight of the Christmas season. Families gather to kick off Christmas celebrations in a beautifully decorated sanctuary. As we light Christmas eve candle, we remember the reason for our celebration. The story of Christmas is placed in the context of Christ&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice for us. There is no more appropriate way to begin Christmas than by receiving the most precious gift, His body broken for us and His blood shed for us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Mary's Song</title>
 		<link href="/video/marys-song"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/marys-song</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we approach Christmas day, we are often overwhelmed with the stress of the holiday season. The hustle and bustle of buying gifts and preparing food often overshadow the true meaning of Christmas. On this third Sunday of Advent, we consider Mary&amp;rsquo;s response to God&amp;rsquo;s intervention in her life. It is a response of giving. May we be challenged through this story to submit our lives to God&amp;rsquo;s purposes. Luke 1:39-55&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Into 2013</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Into-2013"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Into-2013</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we come to the close of another year, we often reflect on where we
have been and where we are going. As a church, 2012 has been a
particularly eventful year. We changed our Sunday morning schedule in
the spring and hired additional staff in the summer. Both of these
decisions involved a lengthy discernment process that began in 2011 and received strong congregational support. Nevertheless, such changes are significant for any congregation. Change is
never easy; it always requires adjustment on some level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say that 2013 will be the year of stability. It would be
nice to sit back and not have to think about significant changes.
Unfortunately, the world keeps changing around us and challenges us to
adapt. As we look into next year, I want to highlight at least two areas
of focus for January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Stewardship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One area of focus for 2013 will be stewardship. While this includes
financial stewardship, it is much more. As a congregation by necessity, we are
shifting leadership and ministry support toward younger attendees and
members. As we have experienced loss in recent years of ageing members (to
death and assisted living facilities), we are finding the pews filled
with younger people. This generation will need to pick up where the
older generation has left off. This is not to diminish the continued
participation but needed care of older members, but we must consider what
will be in the next twenty years. We will need to reconsider how we use
our resources as a part of this process. But at the same time, everyone
needs to be faithful in time, talent and financial resources if First
Baptist Church is to remain viable. We will be having a family
conversation regarding stewardship in the early part of 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;New Communities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been working with a small team to implement new
communities/discipleship initiatives at the beginning of next year. We
have found that discipleship looks a bit different for the younger
generation. While the values are the same, culture has shifted
significantly in the last fifty years. We will be piloting a new
community beginning in February. This community has the potential for
great impact in our congregation and our local community. I hope that some of
you will consider joining this effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will 2013 be a year of change? I am sure that it will be. What will
those changes be and how will they affect each of us? I am not sure.
Yet, I am convinced that God will lead us and direct us toward His
vision for First Baptist Church. We may need to shift our resources; we
may need to try new methods of ministry. May God give us the ability to
hear His voice as we navigate our ever-changing world. May He give us
the courage to adapt to new callings as we continue to fulfill the Great
Commission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Matthew 28:19 NIV) Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>#storyofmylife</title>
 		<link href="/blog/storyofmylife"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/storyofmylife</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve noticed a trend. After recently donning some new leadership and
life roles, many good-natured folks have inquired about what I’ve done
with my life lately (besides create the illusion of a perpetual chaotic
furor). What you’re reading is one attempt towards bucking this trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe good leaders tell stories. While I don’t have the strongest
track record for consistent updates on
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/MatthewPaulHeadley&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mattheadley&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, I’m planning to regularly
carve out time to tell stories here of what God is up to in my life and
ministry. Here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four big things began in my life between July and October of 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;July: Youth Ministry. I was called to join the staff a parachurch
organization called Muncie Area Youth for Christ
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yfc.net/&quot;&gt;(YFC)&lt;/a&gt; as the coordinator for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/MuncieCentralCampusLife&quot;&gt;“Campus
Life”&lt;/a&gt; ministry in
the Muncie Central High School community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;August: Church Leadership. After three years of serving &lt;a href=&quot;http://fbcmuncie.org&quot;&gt;First
Baptist Church of Muncie&lt;/a&gt; as a worship arts
director, I was called to serve as an associate pastor, broadening
my previous leadership role to include outreach ministry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;September: Parenthood. My wife and I met Hannah Joy, an amazing new person who is also our first child. Three words: Beautiful. Scary.
Hilarious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October: Education. For the grand finale of my journey through an
M.Div. with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seminary.edu/&quot;&gt;Northern Seminary&lt;/a&gt;, I began a
chaplaincy internship with the gifted staff in the spiritual care
department at Ball Memorial Hospital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;These new commitments have presented me with some exciting and
formidable challenges. I’ve been humbled by the patience and grace
friends around me have extended as I work to balance these commitments
out. I hope that, as I tell my story and how God is working through it,
you will see him moving in your own life, in our community, and maybe
even the world. Peace!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Giving into God</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Giving-into-God"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Giving-into-God</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week is the last Sunday before Christmas. As we draw near to this sacred holiday, we will consider Mary&amp;rsquo;s response to God&amp;rsquo;s calling in her life. In the first chapter of Luke, we journey with Mary to her relative&amp;rsquo;s house. This 3-4 day journey must have included reflection, doubt but ultimately ends in confirmation. As we follow God, we sometimes experience similar expeditions. Think about it; Mary is told that she is going to be a mother. She is not married, nor has she engaged in unfaithful behavior. How will her relatives believe her story? Joseph will surely abandon her. Will she be deemed insane?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we read this story, we find Mary&amp;rsquo;s response instructive. She models an appropriate posture as God calls her into the difficult. In the early verses of the chapter, we find Mary&amp;rsquo;s response to the angel one of submission and obedience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 1:38 NIV) “I am the Lord’s servant,” Mary answered. “May it be to me as you have said.” Then the angel left her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to wonder if doubts started to creep in a few days later. You have to wonder if anxiety overwhelmed her as she made the trek through the Judaean hill country. I love how this part of the story ends. When Mary shows up at Elizabeth&amp;rsquo;s house, she does not have to deliver a speech. Perhaps she had rehearsed what she would say to her relative. Yet when the door opens, the Holy Spirit takes over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 1:41–42 NIV) When Elizabeth heard Mary’s greeting, the baby leaped in her womb, and Elizabeth was filled with the Holy Spirit. In a loud voice she exclaimed: “Blessed are you among women, and blessed is the child you will bear!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary responds with a song. The song recorded in Luke 1:46-55. It is similar in tone to a Psalm. It celebrates the fulfillment of the prophets through this child. God&amp;rsquo;s promise to Abraham is connected with what God is doing through Mary&amp;rsquo;s pregnancy. But a key phrase grabs my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 1:46–47 NIV) My soul glorifies the Lord and my spirit rejoices in God my Savior,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mary describes an inner peace that contradicts her condition. She speaks of her &lt;em&gt;soul&lt;/em&gt; glorifying God. Her &lt;em&gt;spirit&lt;/em&gt; experiences joy. We discussed (on Sunday) the difference between joy and happiness. Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that God&amp;rsquo;s calling to Mary was not easy. Her world hung in the balance as an unwed mother. Yet an indescribable inner peace glorifies God. Is is possible to &lt;em&gt;rejoice&lt;/em&gt; when God calls us to experience the difficult? As we come to the close of 2012, may we be willing to open our hearts to God&amp;rsquo;s promptings in our life. May Christmas be more than a season, may the spirit of this season extend into 2013. May we learn from Mary what it means to truly give ourself to God.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Re Focus</title>
 		<link href="/video/Re-Focus"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Re-Focus</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our lives are often overwhelmed by the anxiety of our current circumstances. In this Advent season, we are challenged to refocus on the greater realities. As Paul instructed the Philippians church, we must place our anxieties in God’s care. As we are able to do this, we will experience a piece that is beyond understanding. Philippians 4:4-7&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Joy</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Joy"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Joy</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year, our extended family is traveling to Indiana to spend time with us during the holidays. It is been 12 years since Christy&amp;rsquo;s sister has been to our home. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to avoid packing up and traveling south; but now we have to get the house ready for company. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal for you, but for my wife, everything has to be perfect. While I&amp;rsquo;m doing my best to dissuade her from major projects, she will do a bit of house-transformation before the company arrives. Last week, I found myself drawing out 3 foot letters for our mantle; Christy got the idea from Pinterest. She covered the wooden letters in gift wrap. I have to admit, they look pretty cool. The three letters spell out a common Christmas word; J-O-Y. We see this word plastered on billboards, coffee mugs and storefront displays throughout the season. But what does it mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems there is some confusion about the word &lt;em&gt;joy&lt;/em&gt;. Most equate it with happiness. But the word is much deeper. Happiness has to do with our circumstances. If your job is going well, relationships are strong, life is generally good, you might say that you are happy. But joy is has different roots; joy does not depend on our circumstances. The Scriptures instruct us to have &lt;em&gt;joy&lt;/em&gt;; they use the word &lt;em&gt;rejoice&lt;/em&gt;. In our text this week, Paul emphasizes this word. He says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Philippians 4:4 NIV) Rejoice in the Lord always. I will say it again: Rejoice!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He doesn&amp;rsquo;t say it once; he says it twice. Imagine Paul dictating this letter. He tells his scribe, &amp;ldquo;rejoice in the Lord always&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo;Let me make myself clear, I will say it again, rejoice!&amp;rdquo; Why does Paul say it twice? Why does he seem so emphatic? You see, to rejoice is independent of our circumstances. Paul is writing this letter from prison. He is awaiting a trial that may result in his death. It is in this context that he is able to instruct the church at Philippi. Their joy is to be rooted in God. As we study the context, we learn that the church in Philippi will experience intense persecution in the years to come. They will experience not-so-happy circumstances. Nevertheless, Paul encourages them to be joyful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul instructs the believers in Philippi to refocus their attention to God&amp;rsquo;s work in them. He challenges them to place their current anxieties at the feet of God; God will then exchange their worries for immeasurable peace. As we consider this text, we find this no easy task. Is it possible to trade our anxiety for God&amp;rsquo;s peace? As we gather this week, may God empower us to refocus in this way. May God give us the strength to rejoice, even when life is not happy. May we learn to live in Paul&amp;rsquo;s posture, depending on God in all things, and all circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Expectant</title>
 		<link href="/video/Expectant"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/Expectant</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt; Paul&amp;rsquo;s letter to the Philippians allows us to peer into his heart. He is confident that God will complete the work He began in the Philippians church. He anticipates that this work one day come to an end as Jesus returns. His prayer for the Philippians is that they would also live in this anticipation of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return. As you and I explore this text, we are challenged to live in a posture of expectancy and urgency. God will one day return; this truth should drive us as we live out the gospel in our world. Philippians 1:3-11&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Focused on the End</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Focused-on-the-End"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Focused-on-the-End</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week, we talked about the need for urgency and anticipation in the Advent season. In particular, we discussed the need to look forward to Jesus&amp;rsquo;s second coming. We continue to consider this challenge in the coming weeks. For the next two weeks, we will be surveying Paul&amp;rsquo;s letter to the Philippians. As we examine the introduction, we see the anticipation of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return as a primary focus. On Sunday, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the way in which ancient letters were composed. There is a pattern or style of writing for these letters. As we examine the style, it gives us an understanding of Paul&amp;rsquo;s intentions. The section we will be studying is called a &amp;ldquo;Thanksgiving&amp;rdquo; element. In this part of the letter, the author offers a prayer for the recipient. As we read Paul&amp;rsquo;s prayer, we are able to peer into his heart; we are able to understand what he valued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have children, you pray for them. Sometimes you pray for academic achievement, healthy relationships and spiritual connection with God. You want the best for your kids; the way you pray for them indicates your priorities. In this section of Philippians, we are able to see Paul&amp;rsquo;s priorities for the church at Philippi. He prays for a unified body. If they are together in mind and spirit, it will mean spiritual health for them. Paul says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Philippians 1:10 NIV) so that you may be able to discern what is best and may be pure and blameless until the day of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you see it in the text? Paul understands it necessary for the church to navigate waters of discord and strife. He knows that unity will produce holiness. It will not be easy; but their struggle will be only for a while. He says, &amp;ldquo;until the day of Christ.&amp;rdquo; In other words, when Jesus returns, all will be made right. The church will no longer need to strive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will look at other passages in the Pauline epistles regarding the day of Christ. We will see this day as central to the New Testament writers. And if it was foremost for them, it should be primary for us. As we continue through the season of Advent, may we learn to anticipate Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return. May we learn to balance the here and now with the promise of Christ&amp;rsquo;s return.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>His Return</title>
 		<link href="/video/his-return"/>
 		<updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/his-return</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we approach the season of Advent, we are reminded that it is a season of urgency and expectancy. Jesus called his disciples to this posture of urgency and expectancy as he told them of his second coming. May we learn to live in the same posture as we look forward to Christ&amp;rsquo;s return.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Drunk</title>
 		<link href="/blog/drunk"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/drunk</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is hard to believe that December is almost here. We pulled our Christmas decorations out of the attic this weekend, turned on holiday music and transformed our interior and exterior decorations. We even indulged in a couple of holiday movies. It was a festive time for our family. We began our month-long celebration of Christmas. But Christmas is not yet here. It does not arrive until December 25. It may be more accurate to say that we began the &lt;em&gt;anticipation&lt;/em&gt; of Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Sunday, we celebrate the first Sunday of Advent. Advent is not Christmas. Advent is the season of anticipation prior to Christmas. We often lose sight of this as we have succumbed to cultural understandings of the holiday season. Yet, we should learn to live in Advent. This year, we will follow the lectionary passages during Advent. This year&amp;rsquo;s texts point to the second coming of Jesus. We will spend four Sundays considering the urgent and expectant posture of Scripture regarding Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While various interpretations have confused the matter, Scripture is clear that Jesus will return. This week, we will look at Jesus&amp;rsquo;s description of his return; next week, we will consider Paul&amp;rsquo;s writings to the Philippians about Christ&amp;rsquo;s return. How do we make sense of such a complex issue? When is it going to happen? How will it unfold? What clues do we have in Scripture about it? How are we to respond to Scripture&amp;rsquo;s teaching?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would take pages to unpack these questions. I will not attempt such a feat. Yet, I will point to Jesus&amp;rsquo;s advice to us; we are instructed toward a particular posture. Jesus warns,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 21:34 NIV)  Be careful, or your hearts will be weighed down with dissipation, drunkenness and the anxieties of life, and that day will close on you unexpectedly like a trap.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is Jesus saying? The word &lt;em&gt;dissipation&lt;/em&gt; describes a drunken headache, a hangover. Hangovers make it difficult to focus on work or chores. No doubt, the alcohol steals our attention. Jesus understands the impairment of worldly anxieties. He knows that we have the tendency to be tipsy on the cares of this world. They prevent our urgency, our anticipation of Jesus returning. When is the last time you thought about Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return? I have to admit that His coming does not often receive my focus. I seldom concentrate on Jesus&amp;rsquo;s promise to return. Yet, Scripture writers put intense emphasis on Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return. Jesus tells us to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 21:36 NIV)  Be always on the watch, and pray&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May we learn to share this anticipation. May we shake off the hangover of worldly anxieties. May we clearly look toward Jesus&amp;rsquo;s return with expectancy. I hope you will join as we worship in the season of Advent. I pray that our engagement of these texts will enlighten Jesus&amp;rsquo;s promise and our prayer,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Revelation 22:20 ESV) “Surely I am coming soon.” Amen. Come, Lord Jesus!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Orphans in China</title>
 		<link href="/video/orphans-in-china"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/orphans-in-china</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Katy Kessler, a student at Ball State, will be sharing about her experience this summer. She is an occupational therapy major who worked in an orphanage in China this summer. She will be sharing her story in worship.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Story of Jonah</title>
 		<link href="/video/dont-want-to-go"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/dont-want-to-go</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On November 18, we will worship in a combined worship service at 1045 a.m. The children will share a musical about the story of Jonah. We will also reflect the sermon on the call of God in our own lives. Jonah was more concerned about his own comfort, less concerned about following God’s mission in the world. We are challenged by his story to discard our own plans for God’s mission.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Reluctant</title>
 		<link href="/blog/reluctant"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/reluctant</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, the children will be presenting a musical on the story of Jonah. If you grew up in church, you know the story. A prophet is called by God to go to a savage city called Nineveh. He is hesitant &amp;hellip; no, he flat-out disobeys God. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t go to Nineveh; he takes off in the other direction. A storm batters his ship on his flight from God. In ancient times, tempests of this sort were understood as tantrums of the gods. Jonah&amp;rsquo;s shipmates cast lots to determine who has unsettled the gods. Jonah is identified as the culprit. To make a long story short, he is tossed into the sea, swallowed by a big fish, spit onto dry land. God comes to him a second time. This time he obeys. The story continues with Jonah unenthusiastically making the trek in the right direction. When he arrives in Nineveh, the people respond positively to his message. You might think he would be pleased. Rather, he is disappointed that God has offered salvation to the people of Nineveh. God uses a shade tree to communicate the value of all people to a disheartened Jonah.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reflect on this story, we are reminded of our own tendency to walk away from God&amp;rsquo;s direction. God often calls us to unfavorable places. We resist by ignoring God or even going the other direction. I am not sure how God might be prompting you these days. Perhaps He is calling you to a new vocation or new city. Perhaps he is calling you to greater involvement in a particular ministry. While I cannot determine God&amp;rsquo;s voice in your life, I am certain that He calls us join Him in His mission. Joining God requires us to submit our way to His way. Jonah was not given a choice in the matter. In time, he was pressed to go God&amp;rsquo;s route. Perhaps our promptings will not include being swallowed by a fish. Maybe God will urge us in different ways. But God will not acquiesce to our resistance; he will not change His mind. He will not allow us to opt for plan B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May God give us the strength to heed his calling. May he grant us the joy of walking in His way. May we be unlike Jonah, ready to go with God wherever His mission takes us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>A Closing Scene</title>
 		<link href="/video/a-closing-scene"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/a-closing-scene</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the closing scenes of Genesis, we are reminded that God’s story is not over. As Jacob and Joseph pass from the scene, the promise of deliverance looms. As the curtain closes in Genesis, Joseph is embalmed and lies in an Egyptian coffin. Yet the story of God continues. As we gather, we are reminded of our connection with this story. We are reminded that God’s grace comes to fruition through the work of Jesus. As we connect and live in story of God, we are transformed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Permanent Grace</title>
 		<link href="/blog/permanent-grace"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/permanent-grace</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever received an undeserved gift? Was it difficult to accept? Did you envision someone showing up and taking it away? Perhaps it was hard to believe it could be yours? A few weeks ago, we took a group of teenagers to South Haven, Michigan for the weekend. We rented a couple of cabins attached to a bed and breakfast. Christy and I were able to spend time talking to one of the couples staying in the bed and breakfast. The man shared the story of winning a car. He entered a drawing; his name was announced on the radio. Friends called him to notify him of his fortune. He described peering at the prize in disbelief. Did this really happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have not experienced this dynamic. But I could imagine a too-good-to-be-true feeling accompanying such a win. Maybe they will discover that it was a mistake; they will reclaim the prize and life will be as it should. We all have a tendency for skepticism when we get what we do not deserve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final chapter of Genesis, Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers experience this sort of cynicism. While they have experienced tremendous grace and provision, it is hard to believe that Joseph&amp;rsquo;s forgiveness is permanent. When Jacob dies, they expect justice to prevail. Joseph will finally get even.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 50:15 NIV)  When Joseph’s brothers saw that their father was dead, they said, “What if Joseph holds a grudge against us and pays us back for all the wrongs we did to him?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They fear Joseph. Unwilling to speak to Joseph face to face, they send a message. Like a teenager breaking up with a boyfriend by sending a text message, they nervously ask Joseph for forgiveness. You might remember the earlier conversation between Joseph and his brothers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 45:5 NIV) And now, do not be distressed and do not be angry with yourselves for selling me here, because it was to save lives that God sent me ahead of you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph understands his destiny as ordained by God. He is not planning retribution. In fact, their message causes Joseph to weep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 50:17 NIV) When their message came to him, Joseph wept.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The brother&amp;rsquo;s mistrust was painful. While he offered elaborate exoneration, his brothers doubted the permanence of his grace. They did not get it. They struggled to accept what they did not deserve. Joseph responds as he did earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 50:20 NIV) You intended to harm me, but God intended it for good to accomplish what is now being done, the saving of many lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us struggle to receive God&amp;rsquo;s grace. Even when we are able to accept what we do not deserve, we secretly wonder if our accounts will be audited. Will God decide to take a closer look and change His mind about us. We are like the brothers in this story. Yet, God&amp;rsquo;s grace is not temporary. The author of Hebrews reminds us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Hebrews 10: 23) Let us hold unswervingly to the hope we profess, for he who promised is faithful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God will not change his mind. Shifting circumstances will not alter His body broken for us nor his blood shed for us. May we learn, like Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers, to live in God&amp;rsquo;s permanent love for us. May we rest in the reality of his unchanging, undeserved, unconditional and absolute forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Destiny of Jacob's Sons</title>
 		<link href="/video/destiny-jacobs-sons"/>
 		<updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/destiny-jacobs-sons</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In Genesis 49, Jacob calls his sons to his deathbed for a blessing. He speaks powerful words that shape generations to come. His sons, forming the twelve tribes of Israel, will prepare the way for God to enter the world through Jesus. As the book of Genesis nears its end, we are reminded that the story continues as the people of God are now formed.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Family Tree</title>
 		<link href="/blog/family-tree"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/family-tree</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I had an opportunity to connect with a bit of my family history. Dawson, Levi and I were traveling in the countryside of Georgia; we were on our way back from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freshairbarbecue.com/&quot; title=&quot;Home - Fresh Air Barbeque&quot;&gt;Fresh Air BBQ&lt;/a&gt; in Jackson. We passed my great-grandfather&amp;rsquo;s farm which sparked my interest in my lineage. We stopped by the land, walked around and even came across an old family cemetery. On that same visit to Georgia, my uncle gave me a copy of a written history of this land. It was fascinating to explore this story. While the story was filled with details, including specific dates, people and even copies of their wills, reading it raised my curiosity. I wondered how the various family lines developed. I wondered about the siblings. Where did they end up? Were there untold stories of love, war, romance, tragedy? How did their lives play out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we come to the final chapters of Genesis, we are given insight into the lineage of Jacob&amp;rsquo;s sons. On his deathbed, Jacob blesses his sons and prophesies about their descendants. We are reminded that Genesis is not an isolated story; it is the base for the remaining story of Scripture. It is the foundation for the people of God. The story does not end with the final verse of Genesis; it continues and includes many twists and turns. Eventually, the story includes Jesus&amp;rsquo;s arrival; His life, death and resurrection is the pinnacle of the story that begins in Genesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we gather at the Table to remember Jesus&amp;rsquo;s sacrifice for us this week, we are reminded that God was planning His work all the way back in Genesis. We are reminded that our lives are impacted by a larger story. We are included in this story as we live in God&amp;rsquo;s Kingdom. May we fall in love with God&amp;rsquo;s story. May we yearn to learn and live in His story. May we consider our role in His story and how our lives impact generations that follow us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Surprise Blessing</title>
 		<link href="/video/surprise-blessing"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/video/surprise-blessing</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we near the conclusion of the book of Genesis, Jacob is near death. Joseph and his sons pay a visit to his ailing father. Jacob’s actions of adopting and blessing his grandsons remind us that God often moves in surprising ways. As we learn to follow God, we discover that He often acts and moves in ways that we would not plan. Genesis 48&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Surprise</title>
 		<link href="/blog/surprise"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/surprise</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When is the last time you experienced a surprise? When did things turn out in a way different from what you expected? A few weeks ago, Dawson, Levi and I made a trip to Springfield, Illinois. Levi and Dawson wanted to attempt the Joe Rogers Chili Challenge (it was featured on Travel Channel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.travelchannel.com/tv-shows/man-v-food&quot; title=&quot;Man v. Food : TV Shows : Travel Channel&quot;&gt;Man vs. Food&lt;/a&gt;). You have to eat one bowl of Firebrand Chili and you get your name posted on the wall. It is no easy feat. To my surprise, both Dawson and Levi completed the challenge. Levi astonishingly was the youngest to ever complete the challenge. You can watch a video of Dawson &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T1ETfUFNvC8&amp;amp;amp;feature=plcp&quot; title=&quot;Dawson eating Joe Rogers - YouTube&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and Levi &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Io1h9aT6iGo&amp;amp;amp;feature=plcp&quot; title=&quot;Levi at Joe Rogers chili - YouTube&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. I was surprised at how it all turned out. I thought I would be encouraging the boy&amp;rsquo;s effort as we walked out; yet we left celebrating their victory over the Firebrand Chili.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s text leaves us surprised. Jacob is near death and ready to bless his sons. As you may know, it was common practice to bless the oldest son, passing on the family name, land and leadership. Yet Jacob has an alternative plan. As we have seen before, God likes to mix it up; His ways are unpredictable. Join us on Sunday as we walk though Genesis 48 together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we reflect on this story, we are reminded that God&amp;rsquo;s calling cannot be mapped out. We are challenged with a willingness for flexibility. We are often adverse to change, unwilling to carry out ministry in a different way. Maybe God would surprise our methods with new callings. May we consistently be open to God&amp;rsquo;s surprises. May we be willing to follow him into the unknown, the difficult, the new.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Cultural Changes</title>
 		<link href="/blog/cultural-changes"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/cultural-changes</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are living in a transitional period of time in the life of First Baptist Church Muncie. In many ways, we find ourselves in a drastically different world. Muncie is not the same city that it was 50 years ago; the world is not the same world. We have moved from being in the center of the community to being on the fringes. I am not talking about geographically, but culturally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who&amp;rsquo;ve been around a while, you may notice more empty pews these days. This is not a characteristic unique to First Baptist Church Muncie. It&amp;rsquo;s happening all over the country. Thom Rainer tells us that &lt;strong&gt;65%&lt;/strong&gt; of the Builder generation (born before 1946) attends church on a weekly basis.  The next generation (Boomers, born between the years 1946 and 1964) is about&lt;strong&gt; 35%&lt;/strong&gt;. Their kids (Generation X, born generally from the early 60s to the early 80s) attend church at rates around &lt;strong&gt;15%&lt;/strong&gt;. The youngest generation (termed Generation Y, born from the mid 80s on) attends church at about &lt;strong&gt;4%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is mind boggling to see such a drop in church attendance. No doubt, our world is changing. It is clear that we cannot continue to pretend that we exist in 1950. We are called, as a congregation, to navigate these cultural changes as we follow the Spirit of God. In many ways, we are returning to the world much like the early church. We, as the church, are no longer in the center of society. We no longer have the prestige, the power, the privilege of building a big building and watching droves of people flock through our doors. Our posture will need to change; we will have to focus outwardly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of young adults has been discussing the cultural shifts and considering ways to navigate the changes in our world. At the beginning of 2013, a small group will be experimenting with new models of ministry, in order to reach our community with the message of Christ. I hope that each of you will pray that God will direct First Baptist Church Muncie as we respond to God&amp;rsquo;s leading. I am sure that God will resource this congregation to fulfill His calling. You will hear more of these experimental ministries in the coming months. I mentioned them now so that you will join me in praying for God&amp;rsquo;s leading as we plan.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Jealousy</title>
 		<link href="/blog/jealousy"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/jealousy</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to be jealous? Sometimes you read of a jealous boyfriend or girlfriend. They are careful about their significant other; they don&amp;rsquo;t want anyone else to share in their relationship. Other times you hear of jealous siblings. They find joy in the failures of their brothers and sisters. Somehow, they feel as though they are lifted up when others fall. Surely, jealousy is a sin. We are reminded in Scripture to exhibit an attitude of gratefulness in contrast to jealousy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core of jealousy is a forgetfulness of what we have been given. We focus on what others have received, neglecting our own gifts. We also use the word envy to describe such behavior. We speak of someone as “green with envy” when they are upset by the fortune of another. We have all felt this way at one time or another. Maybe it was a job promotion for a coworker or a successful test score for a sibling. We are unable to celebrate the good in their life because we are upset that we did not receive. When we harbor such feelings, we fail to be grateful for the gifts that God has given us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s story, Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers relocate to Egypt in order to survive the famine. Significant grace is extended and spite of their previous failures. They had sold their brother into slavery; they did not deserve to be rescued. But in this story, they are given another chance to respond. Joseph blesses his brothers with new clothes. Again, they receive what they do not deserve. But they will be tested. Benjamin receives five new garments. As before, favoritism is given to one brother. How will be other brothers respond? Twenty years earlier, they responded with jealousy and sold the privileged brother into slavery. Joseph knows their tendency. He warns them,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 45:24 NIV) &amp;hellip; Don’t quarrel on the way!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems kind of crazy that this would be a possibility. They had been given far more than they deserved. Grace has been extended to them. Why would they quarrel? They should be celebrating. But when we stop and think about it, we have all reacted in this way at one time or another. Our tendency is to focus on what we do not have rather than what we have been given. Our tendency is to be jealous of our siblings, our coworkers, our neighbors. This story is a reminder to choose gratefulness over jealousy. It is a reminder that we have been given what we do not deserve. We have no reason to be jealous, to be envious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we delve into this week&amp;rsquo;s story, may we be reminded of our own propensity to focus on what others have received. May we be reminded of the tremendous grace that God has given each of us through Jesus Christ. And may this grace overpower our temptation to focus on what others have received.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Office Hours</title>
 		<link href="/blog/office-hours"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/office-hours</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, my son&amp;rsquo;s friend (a middle schooler) asked me a question. Knowing that I am a pastor, he wondered about my work week. &amp;ldquo;What do you do all week?,&amp;rdquo; he asked, &amp;ldquo;Do you clean the church or something?&amp;rdquo; He pictured me sitting in my office during the week with little to do. Maybe vacuuming the sanctuary or cleaning windows would keep me from getting too bored. While we may laugh at this kid&amp;rsquo;s honesty, perhaps some of you wonder how I spend my time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is honest to say that I never run out of work. Many high-profile pastors have struggled with issues of life and time management. Some have neglected their families in light of a &amp;ldquo;higher&amp;rdquo; calling. Others have neglected their bodies, failing to exercise and eat right due to hurried schedules. A few weeks ago, Matt and I spent an entire day outlining our job/ministry descriptions. It became clear that we rarely work a 40 hour week; most of our weeks are 55-60 hours. So what takes up all this time? Why are pastors so busy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Matt and I serve different roles in this congregation, our work patterns are similar. We spend time preparing sermons or planning worship, leading teams of volunteers in ministry, reading current literature on theology and church life, caring for those who are sick or bereaved, communicating (through church publications or blogs), connecting with the larger Muncie community and spending time in relationship with people. Our work day is not 9-to-5, it is unpredictable and we don&amp;rsquo;t always have a weekly pattern. Evening meetings and late night emergency calls sometimes interrupt family time and sleep. Indeed, we have to work hard to keep balance in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it may be difficult to define the work of a pastor, the primary purpose of our role is to lead this congregation in following the calling of God in our lives. This may involve conversation in a coffee shop, lunch with someone who is struggling, a visit with a hospital patient, connecting with other church leaders in the community or sequestering for prayer and study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our work often needs to take place outside of the church office. Because of the fluctuating nature of our work, it is difficult to predict where we may be at any given time on any given day. If you drive to the church office, you may or may not find us there. Nevertheless, I want you to know that your pastoral staff is accessible. Our cell phone numbers are published in the church bulletin; please feel free to call or text us. We will gladly speak with you on the phone or schedule an appointment. Some may feel hesitant about calling; it may seem that your concern or question is insignificant. Therefore, we are providing a staff contact request form in the church office. Please fill free to fill this out to request a contact with Will, Robert, Matt or myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a 9-to-5 job seems appealing; predictability in schedule offers benefits. However, I love the work that God has called me to. And while I am rarely needed to vacuum or clean windows in the church, I do receive such assignments at home.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Extreme Grace</title>
 		<link href="/blog/extreme-grace"/>
 		<updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/extreme-grace</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we lived in Springfield, Illinois, a friend (and member of our church) worked on the Governor&amp;rsquo;s staff. I was pleasantly surprised when he offered me and Christy tickets to the Inaugural Ball. It was pretty cool to be involved in a VIP event of this sort. Our coats were taken at the door; we were invited to enjoy an unbelievable display of prime rib, seafood and all kinds of hors d'oeuvres. We were able to dance, feast and rub shoulders with celebrities. We clearly did not belong at the event. I was a youth pastor, not a political supporter. Yet, we enjoyed the elevated treatment for one evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s story, Joseph&amp;rsquo;s brothers make the trek to Egypt in search of food. When they arrive, Joseph recognizes them, but they don&amp;rsquo;t know Joseph. Joseph has a plan. He accuses the brothers of espionage. Terrified, they return home only to find the silver (the money used to buy the grain) in their bags. Now they will be accused of robbery. It seems that everything is going wrong. They interpret their misfortune as God&amp;rsquo;s punishment for selling Joseph into slavery. They are instructed to return with their younger brother, Benjamin. In time, they return because of the severity of the famine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they arrive in Egypt (for the second time), they are frightened, uncertain; they fear they will be enslaved or killed. But their treatment is not what they expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 43:33 NIV) The men had been seated before him in the order of their ages, from the firstborn to the youngest; and they looked at each other in astonishment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They could not believe what was happening. In their minds, they deserved death. They sold Joseph into slavery and God was enacting revenge. You could also make the case that Joseph should have taken his chance for retaliation. However, they are invited to feast, to enjoy the plenty in Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 43:34 NIV) When portions were served to them from Joseph’s table, Benjamin’s portion was five times as much as anyone else’s. So they feasted and drank freely with him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Benjamin gets more food, but all the brothers are feasting and drinking freely. This is a beautiful story of grace. The brothers are astonished by such generosity. Their treatment defies fairness. Yet, they receive and are blessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we think about this story, we will come to the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Table together on Sunday. We are welcomed to a table that we don&amp;rsquo;t deserve. We have experienced an abundant grace that covers our sins. It is crucial that we live in this grace each day. I hope that you can join us on Sunday as we explore this story and remember together the blood shed for us, the body broken for us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Reliance</title>
 		<link href="/blog/reliance"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/reliance</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In our culture, we are often told that we can accomplish whatever we want. We simply need to give it enough energy, focus; if we simply work hard enough, it will be ours. While there is merit in such advice, we may want to rethink how we guide our children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s story, Joseph is finally released from prison. His long awaited emancipation comes as a result of dream interpretation skills. His freedom did not come as soon as Joseph may have hoped, but it comes nonetheless. The cupbearer forgot to bring up Joseph&amp;rsquo;s name on his initial release (Gen. 40:23). Yet when Pharaoh experienced dream problems some two years later, he recalls the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 41:12 NIV) Now a young Hebrew was there with us, a servant of the captain of the guard. We told him our dreams, and he interpreted them for us, giving each man the interpretation of his dream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did Joseph interpret the dreams, but he nailed it. Maybe he would be able to help Pharaoh. So Joseph is cleaned up and brought before the King. Pharaoh tells Joseph his dream and asked him if he would be able to interpret it. I love Joseph&amp;rsquo;s response. It may be a clue as to why God would have chosen Joseph. Look at how Joseph responds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 41:16 NIV) “I cannot do it,” Joseph replied to Pharaoh, “but God will give Pharaoh the answer he desires.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This verse is key. Joseph does not strut in, celebrating his ability to interpret dreams. He humbly confesses that he is incapable without God&amp;rsquo;s assistance. Joseph is reliant on God&amp;rsquo;s power. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s dependence on God models the proper posture for you and me. God does incredible things through Joseph. In fact, in one day he goes from a prisoner to second in command in Egypt. One might chalk up the success to Joseph&amp;rsquo;s ability. Yet the author of Genesis credits his humility and willingness to be used by God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pharaoh notices that Joseph has an intense connection with God. He wants someone like this in charge during the prophesied famine. Pharaoh says to Joseph,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 41:39 NIV) Since God has made all this known to you, there is no one so discerning and wise as you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I doubt that Pharaoh understood Joseph&amp;rsquo;s connection with God. Yet he understands that Joseph operates out of a power not his own. He senses Joseph&amp;rsquo;s ability to remain dependent on God. In a world where self-esteem and self-promotion are valued, may we learn to rely on God. May we learn to exhibit the posture of Joseph. May we confess our inability as we seek God&amp;rsquo;s ability to do the impossible through us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Disappointed</title>
 		<link href="/blog/disappointed"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/disappointed</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about you, but I hate going to the grocery store on my way home from work. Long lines are common at this time of the day. I guess everyone waits until they are heading home from work to stop by the store. You have to stand there and wait! The magazines at the checkout counter may entertain for short time; but after a bit, I find myself impatient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is waiting so hard? It seems partly because we live in a world of instant gratification. We can grab dinner without ever having to emerge from our vehicle. If our order is incorrect and we have to walk into the restaurant, we are irate. In a busy and hurried world, waiting is not easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our story this week, we find Joseph in prison. You may remember that he is incarcerated for allegedly raping Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife. Unjustly accused, his time in prison must have tested his patience. In time, Joseph encounters two men disturbed by dreams. The cupbearer and the baker are two of Pharaoh&amp;rsquo;s trusted servants. We are not sure how they ended up in prison, but they must have offended Pharaoh in some way. Joseph, in charge of all the prisoners, has an opportunity to get to know these men. God gives him the ability to interpret their troublesome dreams. For one, the dream meant freedom; for the other, it meant death. As the cupbearer finds freedom, it seems Joseph&amp;rsquo;s will get his ticket out of prison. Yet we read,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 40:23 NIV) The chief cupbearer, however, did not remember Joseph; he forgot him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This must have been a stunning disappointment for Joseph. It seemed that God had given him the ability to interpret the cupbearer&amp;rsquo;s dream so that he would be granted freedom. It appeared that God was moving Joseph toward freedom. Yet Joseph finds himself let down and questioning God&amp;rsquo;s intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us who know the end of the story, we are okay with Joseph being in prison a bit longer. But for Joseph, dismay and doubt must have ruled his thoughts. You see, he did not know the story&amp;rsquo;s ending. He had no idea what God was going to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You and I often find ourselves in this place. Perhaps we&amp;rsquo;re disappointed because God isn&amp;rsquo;t providing in the way we imagined. Maybe a job application was refused, a scholarship was denied or medical report returned ominous results. We are left questioning, doubting or disappointed. In times like these, we must learn to trust the One who sees the future, the One who determines all things. Joseph&amp;rsquo;s story reminds us that God&amp;rsquo;s timing is perfect. May we learn to trust as we wait on God. May we learn that He has our best interests in mind. He is faithful, no matter our circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Joseph</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Joseph"/>
 		<updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Joseph</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to go to church to know story of Joseph. Popular Broadway musicals have familiarized Americans with the main characters of the story. Last year, we attended a local production of &lt;em&gt;Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat&lt;/em&gt;. I remember having to hide my 7-year-old&amp;rsquo;s eyes during the scene with Potipher&amp;rsquo;s wife. No doubt, the story is anything but boring. As we come to chapter 39 this week, we delve into the real life circumstances of Joseph. While he finds himself in an advantageous situation as a caretaker in Potipher&amp;rsquo;s house, he is challenged with the advances of Potipher&amp;rsquo;s promiscuous wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is easy to see the pitfalls of engaging in an adulterous relationship with your boss&amp;rsquo;s wife, one could argue that it was in Joseph&amp;rsquo;s best interest to meet her demands. In fact, Joseph was a slave. He could have easily justified giving into the owner&amp;rsquo;s wife&amp;rsquo;s orders. But Joseph had other reasons for rejecting her advances. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t simply that she was unattractive. Joseph was primarily concerned with his relationship with God. His response was,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 39:9 NIV) How then could I do such a wicked thing and sin against God?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph was solely concerned with how his actions would measure up to God&amp;rsquo;s standard. His chief consideration was to remain obedient and faithful to God. Even so, you might think that such high moral standards would be rewarded. Perhaps Potiphar would promote Joseph for his impeccable judgment. Maybe God would grant Joseph freedom for continual obedience, day after day. After all, Joseph was doing the right thing. How could anything go wrong?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you read the story, you find that Joseph actions land him in prison. Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife accuses Joseph of rape and when it is Joseph&amp;rsquo;s word against hers, Potiphar believes his wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we consider the story, we often find ourselves in similar lures. Maybe our temptations are not so direct (we probably don&amp;rsquo;t have someone asking us to sleep with them every day). But we face temptations nonetheless. Fudging an expense report or relating a couple of mistruths might be considered &amp;ldquo;just part of the job.&amp;rdquo; And when we refuse to participate, we are penalized. How do we deal with similar enticements?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is not always easy, we have to go back to Joseph&amp;rsquo;s focus. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t considering how his behavior might impact his job or standing in Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s house. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t weighing the reaction of Potiphar&amp;rsquo;s wife. He was simply focused on God, on God&amp;rsquo;s Word. And when he measured his potential behavior against God&amp;rsquo;s standards, the choice was easy. He was not willing to sin against God. In this case, it cost Joseph dearly. For the next several years, he may have wondered what life would be like if he had made a different choice. But in the end, God was faithful to reward Joseph&amp;rsquo;s action (or in this case, lack of action). As we face our own decisions, our own temptations, may we remember that the right decision doesn&amp;rsquo;t always produce favorable outcomes (at least initially). But as we follow God&amp;rsquo;s leading, we can be certain that God will be faithful to those who faithfully follow his commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Struggle</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Struggle"/>
 		<updated>2012-08-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Struggle</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jacob&amp;rsquo;s story is quite remarkable. As a baby coming out of his mothers womb, he is grabbing the heel of his brother. He spends most of life scheming and conniving; he gets his brother&amp;rsquo;s birthright and blessing, his uncle Laban&amp;rsquo;s daughters (he really only wanted one of them) and now significant possessions of animals, servants, etc. Maybe Jacob is ready to retire and enjoy fishing and playing golf. But God is not finished with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same way that God called his grandfather Abraham, God now issues instructions to Jacob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 31:3 NIV)  Then the LORD said to Jacob, “Go back to the land of your fathers and to your relatives, and I will be with you.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is some dispute about Jacob&amp;rsquo;s integrity. Laban&amp;rsquo;s sons accuse him of cheating his father-in-law. This would not be out of character for Jacob. Perhaps it is all a matter of timing; Jacob decides to follow God&amp;rsquo;s calling and return to the land of his father Isaac. There is one problem. Esau. The last time they talked, Esau was bitter, angry and ready to kill Jacob. Twenty years have passed; has Esau forgiven Jacob? How will this all work out? Jacob must have been nervous. Yet God promised to be with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way, Jacob meets a group of angels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 32:1 NIV) Jacob also went on his way, and the angels of God met him.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They help Jacob scout out the situation with Esau. The initial reports are not good for Jacob. Esau has 400 men and is heading his way. This tension sets the context for this week&amp;rsquo;s study. Jacob divides his family into two camps and spends the night alone. During the night, he has a personal encounter with God. We are told,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 32:24 NIV) a man wrestled with him till daybreak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sun rises, Jacob is sure that this man is God himself. While Jacob&amp;rsquo;s entire life had been one of wrestling, struggling, this encounter is significant for him. This intimate encounter with God will change everything. He will now have a new name, a new outlook on life. Jacob&amp;rsquo;s relationship with God has been up and down. We have seen him worship, tithe (Genesis 28). Yet life patterns of deception, trickery often prevail. In this overnight struggle, God subdues Jacob and Jacob is blessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us have wrestled with God on some level. We grapple to overcome sin and faithfully follow a God who gave himself for us. Join us on Sunday as we explore the story of Jacob wrestling with God.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Tables Turned</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Tables-Turned"/>
 		<updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Tables-Turned</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s story is anything but boring. Our study through Genesis has been full of twists and turns, faith, deceit, love, rejection, pain, sorrow, miracles and rejoicing. We sometimes find ourselves identifying with one or more characters in the story. This week&amp;rsquo;s story includes quite the cast. For the last few weeks, we have been following Jacob. So far, he has been anything but impressive (in terms of faith). He has deceived his brother and father; he escapes to his uncle&amp;rsquo;s house to avoid getting killed. This week, we pick up with his arrival in his homeland. Little does Jacob know that God is about to turn the table. The trickster is about to be tricked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacob falls in love with a beautiful girl named Rachel. Her father promised her hand in marriage in exchange for seven years of work. The story is one of patience, endurance and love. We read,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 29:20 NIV) So Jacob served seven years to get Rachel, but they seemed like only a few days to him because of his love for her.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe life was going to be OK for Jacob. Sure, he lied to his father and brother, but who&amp;rsquo;s perfect, right? Yet God has not forgotten his scheme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wedding night is a highly anticipated event. You can imagine how intense the excitement must have been for Jacob; he had been engaged seven years. Most engagements in our culture range from six months to 3 years. Finally, the big day arrives. Rachel&amp;rsquo;s father (Laban) throws a party; everyone celebrates. But at some point, Laban substitutes his eldest daughter. We aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly sure when Jacob figures it out. The text simply tells us,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 29:25 NIV) When morning came, there was Leah!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we explore this story in detail on Sunday, we discover the tables turned. Jacob, the deceiver, is deceived. There are many facets to this story, a modern-day soap opera would have to compete for such drama. But in the end, God is doing his work. He is forming a people from this twisted bunch. He is forming his man Jacob into the person He has called him to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a few minutes, listen to Rich Mullins' take on this story and please join us on Sunday as we engage Scripture together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S9FkWlBuls8&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>God's Timetable</title>
 		<link href="/blog/God%27s-Timetable"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/God's-Timetable</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I was working on this Sunday&amp;rsquo;s sermon. I had lunch scheduled with a friend; he has been a pastor for many years. I spent the morning doing research and studying the passage. When I broke for lunch, my friend and I spent some time talking about this story. One verse puzzled me, or at least  caused me to doubt my memory. I did not remember it being in the Bible. When I asked my friend about it, he confessed the same lack of memory. A few weeks later, I was asked to lead a devotion at a denominational gathering. In a room with about ten other pastors, I shared the same verse. Following the devotional, several of the pastors admitted the same failure to recall this detail. So here it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many stories of barren women in the Bible. The more famous include Hannah and Sarah. Their heartache and sense of failure cannot be overemphasized. A woman&amp;rsquo;s value was strongly connected with her ability to reproduce. We all remember these powerful stories of God providing for these women. What I did not recall was that Rebekah was also barren. Do you remember last week&amp;rsquo;s story? Abraham&amp;rsquo;s servant traveled to a distant land (Abraham&amp;rsquo;s home country) and finds Rebekah. She is a beautiful virgin seemingly picked by God as Isaac&amp;rsquo;s wife. Miraculously her family agrees to release her to Isaac. It seemed that the promise of Abraham&amp;rsquo;s great nation would be fulfilled. But here is the kicker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 25:21 NIV) Isaac prayed to the LORD on behalf of his wife, because she was barren.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just one sentence; the author of Genesis does not dwell on her suffering. In the same verse, we are quickly told,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 25:21 NIV) The LORD answered his prayer, and his wife Rebekah became pregnant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is why we did not recollect this detail; it happens so fast in the text. But if you look a bit deeper, you realize that Isaac was 40 years old when he marries Rebekah; he is 60 when the twins are born. Twenty years of praying; twenty years of questioning God. How could we have missed this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever felt like God was oblivious to your suffering? Have you ever wondered if God hears your prayers? Have you felt like you misread God&amp;rsquo;s direction in a given decision? Isaac must have questioned if Rebekah was the right choice. Rebekah must have doubted her decision to leave her family. For twenty years, they prayed for God to move, to act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we prepare for Sunday&amp;rsquo;s text, it is worth noting that God&amp;rsquo;s timetable is not always the same as ours. God may seem to be silent, inactive or insensitive; yet we can be assured that He is not. We are not sure why He allowed Isaac and Rebekah to wait for so long. Yet Isaac continued to exhibit faith in God&amp;rsquo;s plan; he prayed for a child. May we remember this detail and not lose sight of this truth as we wait on God.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Seeking God's Direction</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Seeking-God%27s-Direction"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Seeking-God's-Direction</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we step into the month of August, we are nearing the one year mark of our discernment process regarding church staffing. In August 2011, church leaders (a combined team of Church Council and Diaconate) entered a process of discerning; the question was future staffing at First Baptist Church. We embarked on a journey that took us through several activities (a prayer vigil, listening sessions, exploring outside sources and deliberation among leaders). The leadership team concluded that God was leading us toward an additional staff person who would have broad responsibilities; yet his/her focus would be in outreach and worship. This decision was presented to the congregation in October. A consensus vote revealed overwhelming support for this direction. Last winter, a search team was formed to identify a candidate to fill the position. The search team has been working for months surveying profiles, contacting potential candidates and interviewing candidates. They have taken their work seriously; they have offered their best to determine God&amp;rsquo;s leading in this matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these efforts have led to a unanimous recommendation. The search team is proposing that we hire Matt Headley as Associate Pastor at First Baptist. Matt has been active in pursuing God&amp;rsquo;s direction over the past few months. In the meantime, an opportunity for outreach with Youth for Christ was presented to him last month. After contemplating the options and conversing with Matt, the search committee has determined that Matt serving &amp;frac34; time at First Baptist and &amp;frac14; time with Youth for Christ will benefit everyone. On August 12, the membership will have an opportunity to vote on this proposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This decision has not been in haste; it has taken almost a year to complete. The committee has followed a spiritual discernment process as they have deliberated, and members of the congregation have had input as well. As the church body is asked to finalize the calling of an Associate Pastor in the coming weeks, I want you all to be assured of the due diligence of this team and in the process they have authentically sought and indeed sensed God&amp;rsquo;s leading in this decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Listening to God</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Listening-to-God"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Listening-to-God</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been asked to pull off the impossible? Maybe your boss wanted delivery on an unfeasible time table. Perhaps your spouse requested an unimaginable home project. Completion seemed absurd; but you stepped up and gave it a shot. In this week&amp;rsquo;s text, Abraham asks his servant to locate a wife for Isaac in another country, Abraham&amp;rsquo;s home country. Is there any way that a woman would leave her homeland to join this family in such uncertainty? It is a long shot; yet he ventures into the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story offers a model for our own endeavors. The servant is prayerful and dependent on God as he makes his way to Aram Naharaim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 24:12 NIV) O LORD, God of my master Abraham, give me success today, and show kindness to my master Abraham.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without recounting the entire story, he experiences God&amp;rsquo;s leading him to the right woman. When he conveys his experience to her family, they also agree that God is working. Her father and brother respond:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 24:50 NIV) This is from the LORD; we can say nothing to you one way or the other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final encounter gives Rebekah an opportunity to back out of the deal. Her response matches that of her family; she is faithful to follow God&amp;rsquo;s leading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 24:57-58 NIV) Then they said, “Let’s call the girl and ask her about it.” So they called Rebekah and asked her, “Will you go with this man?” “I will go,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the chief characteristics of this account is a retelling of God&amp;rsquo;s movement. The servant tells the story to Rebekah&amp;rsquo;s family; they discern that God is moving. When the servant meets Isaac after his return, he tells him the story. Again and again, the decision is not based on their preferences; it is based on God&amp;rsquo;s movement. God acts; they respond. God directs; they obey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too often our decisions are based on our individual preferences. We want a particular outcome and so we proceed in our desired direction. We seldom pay attention to God&amp;rsquo;s promptings. We sometimes ask the wrong questions. As we discern, may we emulate the posture of Abraham&amp;rsquo;s servant. Prayer, listening, worship and recounting our experience are part of the mix. May we ask, &amp;ldquo;How is God leading us?&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;What do we want to accomplish?&amp;rdquo; May we be willing to submit our will to His will. May we live out obedience as we hear the voice of God.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Laughter</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Laughter"/>
 		<updated>2012-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Laughter</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Laughter is a good thing, right? Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy a good laugh. We watch sit-coms with virtually no plot-line for the sake of a laugh. We are entertained by comedians who relate the ordinariness of life; they make us chuckle. But laughter can also be very damaging. A group of uncaring school kids can inflict intense agony with their giggles. In this week&amp;rsquo;s text, we find two dimensions of laughter. The first is the laughter of doubt. The second is that of overwhelming surprise and joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are going to bite off a large chunk of Scripture this week. While it is impossible to cover every aspect of the story, we will move quickly through chapters 17-20. God affirms His promise to Abraham and Sarah by changing their names and giving them a specific timeline. Three mysterious visitors show up; Abraham and Sarah provide hospitality to them. While they are eating, God speaks; He offer specifics,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 18:10 NIV) I will surely return to you about this time next year, and Sarah your wife will have a son.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sarah overhears the conversation; she cannot hold it in. She bursts out with laughter. This is the kind of chuckling that comes when you hear the unbelievable. God is not pleased with her response. He questions her outburst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 18:15 NIV) Sarah was afraid, so she lied and said, “I did not laugh.” But he said, “Yes, you did laugh.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t fool God; He hears it all. The next few scenes do not bolster Abraham nor Sarah&amp;rsquo;s reputation. Laughing at God&amp;rsquo;s promise is followed by excusing the sins of a corrupt city (Sodom and Gomorrah) and lying to this guy named Abimelech about their marriage. You have to wonder why God picked this couple. By the time you get to Genesis 21, you are doubting if God chose the right people. We then read,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 21:1 NIV) Now the LORD was gracious to Sarah as he had said, and the LORD did for Sarah what he had promised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can you believe it? God came through; He did the impossible. Even though He is dealing with a doubtful couple of liars, He does what He says He will do. I find Sarah&amp;rsquo;s response intriguing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 21:6 NIV) Sarah said, “God has brought me laughter, and everyone who hears about this will laugh with me.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a different kind of laughter. She no longer doubts God, but giggles with joy at what He has done. Her laughter is extended to everyone who hears this story. We are smiling at God&amp;rsquo;s grace, His provision, His willingness to use the unlikely for His purposes. Do we find ourselves laughing with doubt that God could transform the unlikely situations of our lives? May we be reminded as we encounter this story of God&amp;rsquo;s transformation of our laughter; may we be left smiling in astonishment at His movement in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Following God's Way</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Following-God%27s-Way"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Following-God's-Way</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We talked this week about what it means to follow God&amp;rsquo;s leading into the unknown. As we studied Genesis 12, we remembered times in own lives when God called us into the unseen. Abraham was required to leave his family, his country, to give up his inheritance in response to God&amp;rsquo;s promptings. We admire his faith, his willingness to trust God. Yet, we cannot forget that Abraham&amp;rsquo;s life is full of ups and downs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, David Jones will be teaching on the story of Ishmael. While Abraham was faithful to follow God into distant lands, he and Sarah are not sure God will be able to fulfill his promise through an old barren lady. They develop their own plan; maybe God needs a little help. It seems logical; using maidservants to produce children was an acceptable practice in the ancient Middle East. So Sarah brings it up and Abraham willingly participates in the plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever imagine people like Abraham and Sarah walking around with halos? Do you envision them as nearly perfect in their relating to God? This is simply not the case. The author of Genesis reveals the raw truth. Abraham and Sarah were not convinced that the barren womb could be opened. They chose a path apart from God&amp;rsquo;s leading; they took matters into their own hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are often tempted to do the same. We like to strategize; we would rather go the reasonable path. We are often skeptical that God will step up to the plate. In fact, God often seems slow to action. In this case, Abraham and Sarah complicate God&amp;rsquo;s plan. Their veering has tremendous consequences for all involved. As David relates the story, may we be challenged to submit to God&amp;rsquo;s way. May we recognize that His plan is worth trusting.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Stepping Out</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Stepping-Out"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Stepping-Out</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It was four years ago this summer that our family responded to a call to pastor this church. It was not an easy decision for us. In fact, we had recently (less than a year prior) purchased a new home in Springfield, Illinois with the intention of remaining there. You might recall that I dismissed your first contact; I threw away the carefully chosen materials sent to me by the search team. Yet in time, God revealed that He &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; calling me to Muncie. Moving to a new state required our kids to leave their friends, their church family, the only community that they could remember; they would have to make new friends in a strange place. I was not eager for our family to make this sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four years later, I am more convinced than ever that it was God&amp;rsquo;s plan for us to relocate to Muncie. I could not plan nor foresee what God was going to do with us in Muncie. While He is far from finished, He has allowed us to join this congregation as it moves into its future. I am pleased with the progress we have made; I look forward to leading this congregation in the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our text this week is about a man who was also called to leave his home. His leaving was far more extensive than mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 12:1 NIV) The LORD had said to Abram, “Leave your country, your people and your father’s household and go to the land I will show you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abram&amp;rsquo;s leaving required him to leave everything that defined him. He gave up his home, his inheritance and his extended family to follow God. It must have been tremendously challenging. Yet Abram did exactly what God instructed. God&amp;rsquo;s bidding came with a promise; God promised to increase Abram&amp;rsquo;s name and make a great nation from his descendants. There was one problem; Abram&amp;rsquo;s wife was barren. How was God going to work this out? Was he luring Abram down a dead end road? To make matters worse, when Abram arrived in the &lt;em&gt;promised&lt;/em&gt; land, it was inhabited by pagan people with fortified cities. How would his descendants (if there were any) inherit this land? No doubt, Abram was walking into the unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we study this text on Sunday, we are also challenged to exhibit the same trust in God&amp;rsquo;s leading. God often calls us without giving us all the information. God frequently requires strong dependence on Him. He seldom makes these transitions easy. As we examine the calling of Abram, we will consider ways in which God may be requiring us to &lt;em&gt;step out&lt;/em&gt; in faith.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Fathers</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Fathers"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Fathers</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been asked to read Scripture in a small group Bible study. While some get nervous reading anything in front of others, the Bible can be particularly challenging; it has its share of difficult words. The historical books in the Old Testament are probably the worst, especially the lists of family names. We come to one of those lists (they are called genealogies) this week. It would certainly be hard to preach a sermon over a list of names; yet these lists remind us of a greater truth. None of us live on a historical island. We are connected to our family lineage, both predecessors and offspring. We are products of our fathers and we have the potential to impact our children. It just so happens that this Sunday is Father&amp;rsquo;s Day. Do you see the connection?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would not have the time to relate each story embodied in this list of names. Yet the list reminds us that we have fathers who have shaped us. Some of us share wonderful memories of men who have transformed us in countless ways. We celebrate dads who poured themselves into our lives. Yet every story is not a Pollyanna account; our fathers have not always contributed in positive ways. Father&amp;rsquo;s Day is a painful day for some. Disappointment, regret, hurt and pain characterize our understanding of father. We are a community with various experiences; it is good to share our stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we will use Genesis 11 as a springboard into a discussion on fatherhood. Instead of flipping past the list, relegating any relevance to our lives, we will communicate various experiences of our family lines. At the same time, we will challenge modern day fathers to leave a legacy for future generations. We are living in a list, the ink has not yet dried. Finally, we will point to God as ultimate Father. He is the perfect example of what it means to relate to our children. Where there is brokenness and heartbreak, His love heals. Join us on Father&amp;rsquo;s Day for a time of collective celebration and reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Tall Buildings</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Tall-Buildings"/>
 		<updated>2012-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Tall-Buildings</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We spent this past weekend in Chicago; my kids wanted to ride the Ferris wheel on Navy Pier at night. They wanted to experience overlooking the lights of the city. We had several commitments throughout the weekend, including worshiping at Antioch Missionary Baptist Church in Chicago (what a great experience!), that kept us occupied during the evening hours. We finished at Antioch at 9:40 pm on Sunday; the Navy Pier closes at 10 p.m. We rushed across town to ride the Ferris wheel and filled the final carriage for the evening. As we exited the pier, the Sea Dog Boat Cruise worker approached us. She offered an extreme discount for the final tour of the evening. Even though it was nearly 11 p.m., we decided to take the 75 minute architectural tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we floated down the Chicago River, we were overwhelmed by engineering feats of the last hundred years. The river itself was reversed for sanitation reasons; the project resulted in the connecting of Lake Michigan to the Mississippi basin. Two of world&amp;rsquo;s tallest buildings are visible from the river. The newer Trump Tower actually touches the river; a special cement was developed to keep the weight of the building from sinking into the river. The infamous Willis Tower (formerly Sears Tower) is a highlight of the tour. Dozens of other buildings tower the 38 moveable bridges. We were certainly in awe of such grandeur. As we maneuvered back toward the pier, I remembered that I was preaching on Genesis 11 this Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 11:4 NIV) Then they said, “Come, let us build ourselves a city, with a tower that reaches to the heavens, so that we may make a name for ourselves and not be scattered over the face of the whole earth.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a world of such city-builders looking to make a name for themselves. In fact, we celebrate efforts that break records. The Trump Tower was scaled down after the 2001 attacks; previously it was slated as the world&amp;rsquo;s tallest building. So what is so bad about building tall buildings? Why was God not pleased with man&amp;rsquo;s tenacity for accomplishment in Genesis 11? Why does he break up the party at Babel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we will explore the misfortune of Babel. Mankind was striving for security apart from God, he was looking for notoriety based on his own achievement. God steps in and redirects him toward His purposes. I hope you will join us as we delve into this ancient story. May we consider our own striving for independence and fame apart from God.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Search Team Update</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Search-Team-Update"/>
 		<updated>2012-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Search-Team-Update</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we move past Memorial Day, the swimming pools open and the kids get out of school; summer is here. Schedules slow down a bit or get more hectic, depending on who you are. People begin to travel and weekly church programs become a little more sparse. Yet the work of one team at First Baptist continues strong; the Associate Pastor Search Team is not going on break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some of their work needs to remain confidential, I would like to assure everyone that the team considers their work of tremendous importance. They are fulfilling the mandate of a church-wide decision from last year. As you might remember, a group of church leaders (including the church council and diaconate) participated in a discernment process regarding church staffing in August 2011. They explored options and looked at other church models, entered a purposeful time of listening (this involved a 24 hour prayer vigil as well as small group discussions with various groups throughout the church) and examined the leading of the Spirit. The leaders felt that God was directing us toward the hiring of an associate pastor with major responsibilities in worship and outreach. This is in contrast to hiring a specialized staff person for music, youth, children, Christian Education or missions. As First Baptist no longer has the resources to hire multiple specialists for specific ministries, the leaders sensed that a broadly focused associate pastor would give the church the needed leadership to function as the people of God, carrying out the ministries of the church in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In October, this decision was presented to the congregation in an evening meeting. The broader congregation affirmed the Spirit&amp;rsquo;s movement among the leaders. No doubt, this implementation of this model for church staffing will require adjustment. We will no longer have specific staff for particular ministries; we will have two full-time pastors inspiring, empowering and equipping teams to carry out ministry. The responsibilities for each pastor will be beyond one person&amp;rsquo;s capability if they were to do the ministry on their own, yet this approach enables the congregation to take ownership of various ministries. In many ways, the people of the church will be doing the work of the church; this is in contrast to the staff doing the work of the church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Search Team has been working with denominational leaders as well as reaching out to two seminaries and two Christian universities to discern God&amp;rsquo;s plan for the person to fill this position. The team has also interviewed Matt Headley, recognizing Matt as a strong candidate for the position. Please know that this team is giving due diligence to this process. The team may be prepared to make a recommendation to the church later in the summer. Please continue to pray for their steadfast work. As they discern the leading of the Spirit for the entire congregation, their work is essential for our health and vitality as a church.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>God Regretting</title>
 		<link href="/blog/God-Regretting"/>
 		<updated>2012-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/God-Regretting</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On June 3, I will be in Chicago for graduation; Matt will be preaching. He will deal with a fairly familiar passage, the story of Noah. However, there are a few verses in Genesis 6 preceding the story of Noah; they set the stage for the epic story. We often breeze past these verses to get to the good part. Yet these verses reveal the reason for the flood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other accounts of the flood are found in ancient Mesopotamian literature. One account is the Epic of Gilgamesh. This account portrays a man named Utnapishtim who builds an ark, loads it with animals and survives a violent storm. The pagan account describes gods who are fed up with mortals; they seek to destroy them by sending a flood. The only survivor (Utnapishtim) is tipped off; he escapes the plan of the gods and becomes immortal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some may find these accounts disturbing, they seem to confirm the validity of the biblical account. As we read the text on Sunday, you may be surprised by them. In some ways they sound more like Greek mythology than scripture. Yet they reveal the heart of God at this point in history. While Utnapishtim escapes the plot of the gods (he was never intended to survive), Noah is chosen by God to carry on the human race. But before we get to his story, it is appropriate to live in the tension of God&amp;rsquo;s decision. Before Noah was chosen, God considered total annihilation. Like the gods in the Epic of Gilgamesh, God considered ridding the world of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we read these verses, we feel God&amp;rsquo;s pain. God regrets creating man. That is pretty astounding. How can God regret? Is it possible for God to show remorse for his actions? Yet we read (ESV translation),&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 6:7 ESV) for I am sorry that I have made them&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did God feel this way? What could possibly have prompted God to say this? Join us on Sunday as we explore the reason for the flood. We will consider possible parallels to our own world today and contemplate our appropriate response to God. Perhaps these ancient verses can aid our repentance in a world that often grieves our Creator.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Evil Within</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Evil-Within"/>
 		<updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Evil-Within</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Erik Larson&amp;rsquo;s 2003 New York Times best seller &lt;em&gt;The Devil in the White City&lt;/em&gt; highlights the story of two men. The magical Chicago World’s Fair of 1893 involved architect Daniel Burnham who constructed what many called &amp;ldquo;The White City.&amp;rdquo; With the invention of electricity, he used floodlights to accentuate amazing architectural feats on Chicago&amp;rsquo;s southern shore of Lake Michigan. The book also highlights H.H. Holmes. His work was ambitious but extremely evil. He constructed a three block hotel in which he murdered (some believe) over 200 people. Leonardo Dicaprio has purchased the rights to the story and is in process of producing a movie (opening in 2014).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The similarities and contrasts of these two men is fascinating. While both have grand schemes, Holmes' sinister vision seems to have been bolstered by an unexplainable evil. Holmes targeted single young women in his diabolical plan. Screenwriter Graham Moore, in an interview with Deadline.com, describes Holmes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holmes was a most likable guy who inwardly was a tremendous monster&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we come to Genesis 3 this week, we find a similar character. A serpent approaches the first woman with a villainous proposal. It seems harmless on the surface; yet the impact of her (and eventually her husband&amp;rsquo;s) decision is immense. The story is familiar; we all know what happens. Yet as we enter into the story once again, we are reminded of our own failure, our own tendency for evil. While it is easy to blame Adam and Eve for the brokenness of our world, we have all participated in their actions. Join us on Sunday as we study Genesis 3 together.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>The Gift of Women</title>
 		<link href="/blog/gift-of-women"/>
 		<updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/gift-of-women</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This coming Sunday is Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day. Celebrations for mothers date back to ancient civilizations and today vary among cultures and countries. In the United States, we designate the second Sunday in May to celebrate our moms. Restaurants appreciate the break we give our moms on this day. Kids sometimes do extra chores around the house our create a colorful card. On Sunday in worship, we will reflect on our shared mother, Eve. As we venture through the book of Genesis, it seems appropriate to consider the creation of woman in Genesis 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many are familiar with the story. Adam is placed in a coma while God removes one of his ribs. When he wakes up, he is presented with Eve. They join together in shameless sexuality and serve as models for marriage as God intended. What relevance does this text have for us in the year 2012? How might we approach Mother&amp;rsquo;s Day differently as we engage this text?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is much discussion these days about gender. Gender inequality has curbed discussion of gender differences and roles. While male-dominated cultures have abused and neglected the gifts and contributions of women for thousands of years, a peek into God&amp;rsquo;s original plan may prove insightful. God created gender as a gift. If God intended us to ignore gender, the story would be different. As we explore Genesis 2, we find Adam in desperate need of a partner. He surveys all the animals to determine if one might be appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 2:20 NIV) But for Adam no suitable helper was found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God responds by creating woman; she has all the necessary characteristics. She complements Adam in every way. They are able to fulfill God&amp;rsquo;s design to be fruitful and multiply. A key verse in the story is v. 25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Genesis 2:25 NIV) The man and his wife were both naked, and they felt no shame.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam and Eve in Eden reveal God&amp;rsquo;s plan for gender and sexuality. Our differences in gender should be celebrated, not dismissed. One gender should not dominate the other; both are essential and invaluable. Together, we fulfill God&amp;rsquo;s design for His creation. Both Jesus and Paul point to Genesis 2 as they teach on marriage. This crucial text helps us understand the beauty and value of women. Join us on Sunday as we celebrate the gift of women.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Paradise</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Paradise"/>
 		<updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Paradise</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We were certainly given a break this winter in Indiana; the weather was much milder than usual. I don&amp;rsquo;t mind a bit of cold weather. The changing of the seasons is beautiful. My wife would disagree. She grew up in South Georgia where it rarely gets below freezing. She wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind living in summer year round. Do you like tropical weather? Flowers blooming year round; no coats necessary. If you visit a climate like this, you might even refer to it as paradise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we are going to explore the first created environment for man and woman, Eden. What was this place like? Since they ran around naked or in fig leaves, the climate must have been warm. Was it paradise? That is an interesting word. In English, the word is not necessarily related to the weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;paradise: a place or state of bliss, felicity, or delight (Webster Dictionary)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word in Greek (&lt;em&gt;paradeisos&lt;/em&gt;) includes the dynamic of bliss but refers more specifically to the surroundings. It literally means &amp;ldquo;an enclosed park&amp;rdquo;. It was often used to describe a garden. In the Septuagint (the Greek translation of the Old Testament) the English-tranlated word &lt;em&gt;garden&lt;/em&gt; is rendered &lt;em&gt;paradeisos&lt;/em&gt;. No doubt, there is a connection with the original garden (Eden) and paradise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Jesus is hanging on the cross, he says to the repentant criminal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Luke 23:43) “I tell you the truth, today you will be with me in paradise.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the connection between Eden and Jesus' reference to paradise in Luke 23? Was Jesus referring to restored creation? Are those who place their faith in Jesus going to one day return to Eden? John describes the new heaven and the new earth in Revelation 22. The similarities with Eden are substantial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we compare our broken world to paradise, there is much to be desired. Eden seems more like a pipe dream than a reality. Yet throughout Scripture, we get hints of the restoration of Eden. While our world seems as far away from Eden as it ever has been, Jesus promises to restore, to make all things new. Join us on Sunday as we explore Eden; there is much to learn from initial dwelling of mankind.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Change 2</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Change"/>
 		<updated>2012-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Change</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have lived two Sundays in the new schedule. I know that it has been an adjustment for some of us. The praise band has to arrive early to sound check. Many who were accustomed to arriving for Sunday school at 10:15 now arrive at 9:15. Some Sunday school have been divided or discontinued as a result of the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change is never easy. As we grow older, our bodies change (sometimes letting us down). Our kids grow up, move off to college. Friends relocate to different states. We sometimes have the difficult task of saying goodbye to friends and loved ones as they pass away. Yet we are required to change in life. As God leads us, we respond to his movement. Many times He calls us to adjust. And as we adapt, we experience transformation that would not be possible without change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we enter our first full month of our new Sunday morning schedule, allow me to remind you why and how we discerned the need for this change. Conversation began among leaders in November regarding the need for an adjustment of our Sunday morning schedule. We found that the Sunday school hour was inadequate as far as time for most classes. By the time people arrived for Sunday school, talked a bit and began the lesson, it was time to dismiss. Many classes found themselves with less than 30 minutes. Late worship service included less than half of its participants at the beginning of the service. Many were still in Sunday school and were unable to make it into the sanctuary on time. We&amp;rsquo;re not sure how we needed to change or even if we needed to change the schedule at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We began an intentional Process of Discernment around the issue. This process included a time of exploration of options, a period of listening (which included outside information, people in the congregation, and prayerful consideration of the leading of the Spirit). We then examined the issue in light of our listening. There was an incredible unity among the leaders around the solution. Church leaders then brought the draft schedule to the congregation in January. Everyone was given an opportunity to ask questions, share opinions and discuss the ramifications of the change. Through a consensus vote, the congregation affirmed the discerning of the leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure if you find the new schedule appealing. Maybe you think it is great; maybe you are having a hard time adjusting. In time, we will discover the benefits and liabilities of this change. For now, we trust that our careful discernment was not in vain. We trust that God has led us to this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we make decisions in the future, I hope that we will take the necessary time to discern the leading of the Spirit. Our decisions must not be based on personal preference (or what we perceive is best for &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;). We must continue to ask God for His will, His desire for how we function. While any process is subject to human error, I have confidence that God will honor our discerning, that He will help us navigate the decisions that we must make as a congregation as we submit our will to His.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are concerns that you have regarding the new schedule, please take time to discuss the matter with church leaders. God may lead us to make further adjustments. Our discerning never ends; we continue with open ears as we participate in congregational life under the Spirit&amp;rsquo;s leading.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Rest</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Rest"/>
 		<updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Rest</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever attended a lock-in? If you were in a youth group, the answer is probably &lt;em&gt;yes&lt;/em&gt;. A lock-in usually involves staying up all night. I used to dread these events as a youth minister. I knew that the event would take its toll on me for the next week or so. It was fun staying up all night playing games, watching movies or playing hide-and-seek in the church. The bad part was the next day. I would usually go home and crash, sleeping 4 or 5 hours. I would wake up mid-afternoon and try to stay awake until bedtime. As I got older, these events were harder and harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that our bodies are not designed for this schedule. We are fashioned for 7-8 hours of sleep each night. Somehow our bodies reset during this time and allow us to be productive during the remaining 16 hours of the day. In the same way, we function best when we provide adequate time for relaxing and winding down. If you have worked more than 12 hours in a day, you know the feeling. You feel worn down and your creative energy takes a nose dive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are created by God to function in particular patterns. When we veer too far from this design, we suffer. We learn in the Creation story a distinct pattern for our weeks. God creates for six days and rests on the seventh. It is not that God wanted a break. God is all-powerful and does not need a repose to sustain energy. Yet he rests in order to model a pattern for us. God rests because he designed us to rest. We are in the image of God and function in the patterns of our Creator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent decades our world has shifted dramatically away from understanding proper rest. Join us on Sunday as we discuss the seventh day of Creation. It has extreme relevance to our lives in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Change</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Change"/>
 		<updated>2012-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Change</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;John Lasseter of Pixar Studios was being interviewed by Michelle Norris on National Public Radio. He was discussing the work of computer animation. Norris expressed her impression of the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cars glisten &amp;hellip; It looks like we’re seeing photography&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She then questioned Lasseter,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;With everything you can do with computer generated animation, are there still limitations?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lassester affirmed the limitations, explaining the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The more organic something is in the way it looks or the way it moves, the harder it is to create it with a computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He went on to explain that every frame of a movie takes about seventeen hours. According to the Los Angeles Times, production costs for Pixar films average about $140 million.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the Brooklyn Botanic Garden announced a summer exhibit in which they took super close photos of tree bark. There was very little cost involved. The exhibit was described in these terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;One canvas is magenta red has curling squares of what looked like skin or material; another has furry brown hairs sprouting on green and orange stripes; and on a third, lip-like shapes float on a gray-white background.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contrasting of man-made verses organic/natural reminds us of what Dr. Lewis Foster observed many years ago. He relates,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The closer one gets to something man has made, the more its imperfections are obvious. The more we magnify something God has created, the more we see its perfection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week, we begin a sermon series through the book of Genesis. We open our Bibles to Genesis 1, the story of Creation. The natural world is truly a work of art. Its complex and exquisite details are overwhelming; the vastness of the universe is overwhelming. But how did it all begin? We will walk through the first six days of Creation according to Genesis. As we engage the text, we discover our role as created beings made in God&amp;rsquo;s image.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 
 	<entry>
 		<title>Victory</title>
 		<link href="/blog/Victory"/>
 		<updated>2012-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
 		<id>/blog/Victory</id>
 		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am going to do something this Easter that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have ever done; I am going to be preaching from a psalm. I have preached from the Gospel accounts of the resurrection or even one of Paul&amp;rsquo;s epistles. It may seem strange to go to the Psalms at Easter. However when you look closer, it may make perfect sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that Jesus and the Apostles quoted Psalms more than any other Old Testament book? Did you realize that Jesus quoted from Psalms as he hung on the cross? Jesus certainly saw the connection of His ministry with the Psalms. While many psalms were written nearly a thousand years before Jesus, they have incredible relevance to His life, death, and resurrection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Sunday we will consider selected verses from Psalm 118. While Psalm 22 and 31 (both quoted from the cross) describe the anguish, uncertainty and suffering of the cross, Psalm 118 reflects on the victory of God&amp;rsquo;s provision. On Easter we celebrate the most important truth in history, &amp;ldquo;He is Risen!&amp;rdquo; Yes God ventured to the depths on the cross, but His rising from the dead assures us that his death was not permanent. Look at how pertinent these words are to Easter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Psalms 118:15–17 NIV)  15) Shouts of joy and victory resound in the tents of the righteous: “The LORD’s right hand has done mighty things! 16) The LORD’s right hand is lifted high; the LORD’s right hand has done mighty things!” 17) I will not die but live, and will proclaim what the LORD has done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David (the writer of Psalm 118) uses the same language used by Jesus and the Apostles to describe God&amp;rsquo;s plan in Christ. He talks about gates and capstones. The connection is astounding. Join us on Sunday as we explore Psalm 118 and celebrate the risen Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that we will meet for breakfast at 9:30 am and combined worship at 10:45 am.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 	</entry>
 

</feed>